<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/feed/anime.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-03-07T11:26:02+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/feed/anime.xml</id><title type="html">CodingIndex’s Random Shenanigans | Anime</title><subtitle>A (human) index that likes to code. Also drinks way too much coffee.</subtitle><author><name>James</name></author><entry><title type="html">Your Lie in April</title><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Shigatsu-wa-Kimi-no-Uso/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Your Lie in April" /><published>2021-02-15T01:50:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-02-15T01:50:00+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Shigatsu-wa-Kimi-no-Uso</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Shigatsu-wa-Kimi-no-Uso/">&lt;p&gt;“What, you haven’t watched Your Lie in April? You call youself a weeb???” is the reaction I get when I shyly proclaim that among the 200+ anime I have watched, the highly rated Shigatsu no Uso wasn’t one of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For good reason, really. I guess, I forget :stuck_out_tongue_winking_eye:? &lt;em&gt;Anyway&lt;/em&gt;, putting all that aside, I went into Your Lie in April with high expectations, with my main judging criteria being how they set up the atmosphere for emotional scenes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;atmosphere&quot;&gt;Atmosphere&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah, that’s right. I’m reviewing an anime first and foremost by it’s atmosphere, rather than its story, audiovisuals or character building. I want to explain that it’s due to the anime being of the “Drama” genre, but honestly, it’s mostly because I was bombarded with opinions stating how “emotional” the anime is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my (not-so) humble opinion, atmosphere contributes greatly to the “feels” of a scene; atmosphere is comprised of audiovisuals, pretext, and silences. Your Lie in April is an excellent example of setting up atmosphere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Characters themselves give poetic pretexts, using similes, metaphors and symbolism to express their feelings. Sometimes their feelings are compared to the sea of stars, sometimes to the flow of time, and sometimes to the vibrancy of colors. During the climax of the emotional moment, the audiovisuals turns the poems into visible/audible images, which is enhanced greatly by the classical music playing in the background, until - silence. In a sense, the atmosphere matches perfectly with most classical music pieces, as the ample silence in most pieces becomes more deafening than the music itself, building time for the audience to breathe, and to take it all in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20210215_3.gif&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 400px; width: 100%; margin: 0 auto; display: block;&quot; alt=&quot;Shigatsu no Uso Atmosphere&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center text-gray lh-condensed-ultra f6&quot;&gt;An example of atmosphere | Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pinterest.com/pin/278026976972590889/&quot;&gt;Pinterest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a little hard to put into words, but imagine composing a poem while looking at the stars, with someone playing slow tempo piano music at the side - it is bound to trigger some emotions. In a nutshell, Your Lie in April is an excellent example of setting up atmosphere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;character-building&quot;&gt;Character Building&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is good stuff. You will see a lot of character building in Your Lie in April. Take my word for it, explaining it will ruin the story for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;story&quot;&gt;Story&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your Lie in April is &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; predictable; but the predictability is also its charm. It is &lt;em&gt;because&lt;/em&gt; you can predict the events, that the scenes become more so emotional; to put simply, surprise is an element that overrides most emotions, and it should be used sparingly in a Drama-genre anime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get why people scorn me for having the audacity of calling myself a weeb when I haven’t seen Your Lie in April. This was a great watch, and something that I’ll remember as a fundamental and reference for future drama anime. Place it at the top of your “to-watch” list if you haven’t already watched it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Coding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CodingIndex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James</name></author><summary type="html">“What, you haven’t watched Your Lie in April? You call youself a weeb???” is the reaction I get when I shyly proclaim that among the 200+ anime I have watched, the highly rated Shigatsu no Uso wasn’t one of them.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/3/67177.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/3/67177.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Dungeon ni Deai wo Motomeru no wa Machigatteiru Darou ka III</title><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Dungeon-ni-Deai-wo-Motomeru-no-wa-Machigatteiru-Darou-ka-III/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dungeon ni Deai wo Motomeru no wa Machigatteiru Darou ka III" /><published>2021-02-15T01:40:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-02-15T01:40:00+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Dungeon-ni-Deai-wo-Motomeru-no-wa-Machigatteiru-Darou-ka-III</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Dungeon-ni-Deai-wo-Motomeru-no-wa-Machigatteiru-Darou-ka-III/">&lt;p&gt;From my &lt;a href=&quot;/anime/Dungeon-ni-Deai-wo-Motomeru-no-wa-Machigatteiru-Darou-ka-II/&quot;&gt;previous review&lt;/a&gt;, I mentioned that Season II was meant to be an information-revealing season, so that big “stuff” can happen in Season III.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And guess what, I’m mostly on the mark! Season III presents us with the series’ greatest conflict yet; so controversial that even members of the Hestia familia had differing opinions on the matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So controversial, that even the gods themselves bicker bitterly with one another to no resolution - this is the season that changes the plot of the series forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;story&quot;&gt;Story&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m very happy with the story; although predictable, the authors took the right step forward by introducing a difficult situation for the main characters to handle. This creates opportunities for character development and world development, alongside keeping us, the audience, on our toes as we anticipate what may happen next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, story elements are placed early enough in the season to count certain major events as “consistent” with the lore; for an example of a “major event” it would be something like reviving a person. In other words, for me to exclaim: “yup, that seems legit” to something like reviving a person, the story has to have some plot device early enough in the season to serve as a logical fact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;character-development&quot;&gt;Character Development&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not much of that here, except for the new main character introduced in this season. Arguably, in this context, this might be a good thing; because character consistency to resolve issues the way the viewer’s expect is what we need to see during a turbulent world event. In some anime, where both the character and world grows together, a character’s actions become difficult to understand as the audience simultaneously tries to grasp what is going on with the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Season III was an interesting season, and laid some story elements that can be used in the climax of the later seasons. I hope to see great things from Dungeon ni Deai wo Motomeru no wa Machigatteiru Darou Ka IV!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Coding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CodingIndex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James</name></author><summary type="html">From my previous review, I mentioned that Season II was meant to be an information-revealing season, so that big “stuff” can happen in Season III.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1523/108380.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1523/108380.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Moriarty the Patriot</title><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Yuukoku-no-Moriarty/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Moriarty the Patriot" /><published>2021-02-15T00:40:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-02-15T00:40:00+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Yuukoku-no-Moriarty</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Yuukoku-no-Moriarty/">&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, this is the hidden gem of Fall 2020; perhaps I am too intoxicated by my love for the psychological genre, but I never expected an anime on the ever-so-popular Sherlock Holmes through the perspective of James Moriarty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sherlock Holmes is a repeating concept throughout many media, and individually has many interpretations attached to his name. In the context of anime, I am reminded of &lt;a href=&quot;https://hidannoaria.fandom.com/wiki/Aria_H._Kanzaki&quot;&gt;Aria Holmes Kanzaki&lt;/a&gt; from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://myanimelist.net/anime/8630/Hidan_no_Aria&quot;&gt;Hidan no Aria&lt;/a&gt; series, an anime I consider a classical fundamental to the action-comedy-romance-school combo genre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20210215_1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 400px; width: 100%; margin: 0 auto; display: block;&quot; alt=&quot;Aria H. Kanzaki&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center text-gray lh-condensed-ultra f6&quot;&gt;Aria H. Kanzaki illustrated on the Light Novel Cover | Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://hidannoaria.fandom.com/wiki/Aria_H._Kanzaki&quot;&gt;Hidan no Aria Fandom Wiki&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aria is a descendent of Holmes, but she inherited none of Holmes’ wit and deduction skills - even in a action-comedy-romance-school combo genre anime, a tribute and interpretation of Sherlock Holmes is formed to better tell the story. However, while most media affectionately draw inspirations from Sherlock Holmes, none of them bat an eye on James Moriarty, who arguably is the most complex character in the tales spun from Sherlock Holmes’ legacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;story&quot;&gt;Story&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Moriarty the Patriot, we see an interpretation of the prequel to the Sherlock Holmes novel in James Moriarty’s point-of-view. Minor spoilers: James Moriarty is a composite of &lt;em&gt;three&lt;/em&gt; individuals; William, Albert, and Louis. These three individuals make up Moriarty’s intellect &amp;amp; cunning, nobility, and combat dexterity respectively. This creates an interesting dynamic between the characters, and opens up some possibilities to deviate from the “boring normal” of the typical Sherlock Holmes storyline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite knowing the events that take place within the novel, “Moriarty the Patriot” creates a compelling story by telling it from a different point-of-view, not to mention the how easy it was to follow the plot thanks to the characters’ clear dialogue with one another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20210215_2.gif&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 400px; width: 100%; margin: 0 auto; display: block;&quot; alt=&quot;James Moriarty 'William'&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center text-gray lh-condensed-ultra f6&quot;&gt;James Moriarty 'William' | Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://akashi-tetsuki.tumblr.com/post/631696865472266240/william-james-moriarty-yukoku-no-moriarty&quot;&gt;Tumblr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seeing the perspective of the antagonist of the Sherlock Holmes novels, and his overarching plan to achieve his goals is &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; refreshing - it made me think about how there is no difference in being overly good and overly evil; everyone is righteous from someone’s point-of-view. The true evil, is being neutral to it all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;audiovisuals&quot;&gt;Audiovisuals&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good. I mean, what did you expect? This anime is animated by the same studio in charge of &lt;a href=&quot;/anime/Shingeki-no-Kyojin/&quot;&gt;Shingeki no Kyojin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;/anime/Psycho-Pass-3/&quot;&gt;Psycho-Pass&lt;/a&gt;, and the insanely popular shounen sport animes &lt;a href=&quot;https://myanimelist.net/anime/20583/Haikyuu&quot;&gt;Haikyuu!!&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://myanimelist.net/anime/11771/Kuroko_no_Basket&quot;&gt;Kuroko no Basket&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;worldcharacter-building&quot;&gt;World/Character building&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no need for world building; they are just locations to house the story. In other words, the locations have no real meaning, and can be replaced by any other city in Great Britain and have no impact to the story. The only exception to this is where the story is situated: in Great Britain - a place where nobility rules over commoners like farmers raising livestock. This is the only world-related thing that matters in the story, further serving as a main motive for James Moriarty; hence, is developed to hell and back in the anime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is important for certain characters to remain stagnant in terms of character building, to maintain the integrity of the story. Certain other characters, such as James Moriarty ‘Albert’, go through the typical character growth of resolution after confronting his source of hate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hidden gem :gem: which I personally enjoyed way too much; I even ignored my deadlines to binge the anime. Put this anime somewhere at the top of your anime bucket list, I’m sure you won’t regret it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Coding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CodingIndex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James</name></author><summary type="html">In my opinion, this is the hidden gem of Fall 2020; perhaps I am too intoxicated by my love for the psychological genre, but I never expected an anime on the ever-so-popular Sherlock Holmes through the perspective of James Moriarty.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1464/108330.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1464/108330.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Fire Force Season 2</title><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Enen-no-Shouboutai-Ni-no-Shou/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fire Force Season 2" /><published>2021-02-15T00:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-02-15T00:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Enen-no-Shouboutai-Ni-no-Shou</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Enen-no-Shouboutai-Ni-no-Shou/">&lt;p&gt;This season has more world-building, expanding the possibilities for future instalments of Fire Force. There is ample character development, even in unexpected characters; the fights are engaging to watch, accompanied by modern audiovisuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time, there isn’t much to comment about this season; perhaps the lack of impact Fire Force Season 2 has would have docked more points on its rating, but I believe that this was intentionally done as a precursor to something greater in Season 3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have other anime to watch on your bucket list, it might be better to pursue those first; Fire Force Season 2 might be something to binge when Fire Force Season 3 is announced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Coding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CodingIndex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James</name></author><summary type="html">This season has more world-building, expanding the possibilities for future instalments of Fire Force. There is ample character development, even in unexpected characters; the fights are engaging to watch, accompanied by modern audiovisuals.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1673/107657.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1673/107657.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Dr. Stone</title><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Dr-Stone/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dr. Stone" /><published>2020-12-06T00:45:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-12-06T00:45:00+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Dr-Stone</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Dr-Stone/">&lt;p&gt;Yes, I finally sat down to watch Dr. Stone, another popular anime that took the internet by storm. How can &lt;em&gt;another&lt;/em&gt; shounen anime satisfy the cruel audience that is the internet?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;story&quot;&gt;Story&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story centers around Senkuu, a nerd who has &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; too much science knowledge for a high-schooler. As with good shounen anime, the first episode introduces the scenario in an easy-to-digest manner, even going as far as being quite light-hearted despite the scary outlook of having humanity turn to stone. Within that same episode, we learn Senkuu’s hefty overarching goal of reviving humanity with science to build a scientific civilization in their stone world. Furthermore, we also see Senkuu’s determination and grit to put all of his mind into achieving something, from his feats detailed in the first episode: (i) he counted, second by second, the amount of time passed since his petrification, (ii) built a lab and living quarters from scratch on his own and (iii) still having the energy to express and talk about his huge goal of reviving all of humanity with science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20201206_1.gif&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 400px; width: 100%; margin: 0 auto; display: block;&quot; alt=&quot;Senkuu&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center text-gray lh-condensed-ultra f6&quot;&gt;Senkuu Ishigami | Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://i.pinimg.com/originals/b3/85/69/b385694f382ef98190040916c0efdda1.gif&quot;&gt;Pinterest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, Senkuu will &lt;em&gt;never&lt;/em&gt; compromise and back down from achieving his goal. This is seen consistently throughout “Dr. Stone”, making the characters somewhat predictable, which is characteristic of a shounen anime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Senkuu is also proficient at reading other’s psychology, which makes interactions between characters quite interesting - especially with characters that possess the same psychology reading ability Senkuu has.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the nature of the scenario, the world setting continues to change as the main character explores the world, unlocking locations and story elements which are promptly exploited for character and relationship development among the characters. This makes every episode fresh and exciting to watch, despite the predictability of each character in the anime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;character-development&quot;&gt;Character development&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first half of “Dr. Stone” focuses on introducing new characters; hence, character development was mostly done in the form of flashbacks, conflicts with the antagonist, and the scenario’s need for the characters to survive together. In the second half of “Dr. Stone”, new characters are still introduced via flashbacks and the like, but there is also character development due to budding relationships among the characters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20201206_2.png&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 400px; width: 100%; margin: 0 auto; display: block;&quot; alt=&quot;Ishigami Village&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center text-gray lh-condensed-ultra f6&quot;&gt;Ishigami Village | Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://dr-stone.fandom.com/wiki/Ishigami_Village&quot;&gt;Fandom&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Relationship development in “Dr. Stone” is probably one of its salient points - having a logical mind that can only objectively view the benefits of people’s actions make interacting with others quite difficult. This is seen in the conflicts between Senkuu and the Ishigami Village in the beginning. However, as with all characters, they eventually understand that Senkuu’s way of thinking is &lt;em&gt;entirely&lt;/em&gt; logical, which makes having evil ulterior motives difficult to imagine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is also the part where Senkuu literally forces the village to acknowledge him - you’ll find out what I mean when you watch “Dr. Stone”, assuming you haven’t already. As for the other main characters on Senkuu’s side, we don’t really see much character development other than a few flashback scenes and a promise in a hot spring. The exception is Chrome, who undergoes a change after meeting Senkuu and experiencing hardship with him. This can be inferred from how he changes the way he perceive “sorcery” as “science”, and using his knowledge of science to overcome adversity even under the influence of fear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;audiovisuals&quot;&gt;Audiovisuals&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The audiovisuals are modern and complementary. The best part for audio, though, is a song sang as part of the story (i.e. not the opening and ending).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the “revive all humanity with science” and “build science civilization” that is going on, listening to the song probably had a huge impact onto both the cast and the audience - songs and music is one of the aspects that potentially helped built and maintained civilization. The anime makes no reservation when it comes to reminding us how much time humans spent on building civilization, which is full of contributions from not only science, but music, food, art, poems, books and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The song is good and well-used in the story, therefore the audiovisuals get an extra plus from me due to how well it complements the story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Stone is a good watch, as proven by the internet’s response to the anime. I definitely recommend giving it a watch!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Coding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CodingIndex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James</name></author><summary type="html">Yes, I finally sat down to watch Dr. Stone, another popular anime that took the internet by storm. How can another shounen anime satisfy the cruel audience that is the internet?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1613/102576.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1613/102576.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">ID: INVADED</title><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Id-Invaded/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ID: INVADED" /><published>2020-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Id-Invaded</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Id-Invaded/">&lt;p&gt;I’m a tech guy. I see sci-fi and psychological genre tags, I click. That was how I discovered this anime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;story&quot;&gt;Story&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ID: INVADED has one of the most intriguing first episodes ever. The way the pilot episode introduces the Mizuhanome system and the main characters psychology and thought processes hooks the user in from the first episode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ergo, “first impressions matter”. I was instantly hooked. As the story progresses, I gained a more complete understanding of the scenario. Yet, I continue to be surprised by the elements thrown at me - at one point, I stopped trying to guess what would happen next. However, the main overarching mystery (the “John Cook” guy) in the story was not well-written; by the end of Episode 2, most of the characters have already been introduced, allowing us to use process of elimination to obtain our main culprit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later on in the story, things go from “sci-fi” to “fantasy” - this transition could have broke the anime, but it was well-executed enough such that the story setting did not change too drastically. To some extent, the changes “made sense”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;character-developments&quot;&gt;Character Developments&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be frank, there were not much character development to speak of; normally, that would dock some points for me. However, in “ID: INVADED”, character development &lt;em&gt;would&lt;/em&gt; dismantle the essence of the storyline - in other words, having consistent characters is what makes the story more engaging. This is mostly proven by the main character having the same psychology when in the real world versus inside an “id well” - you’ll understand what I mean when you watch the first episode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a good art style, a reasonable closure to the anime, and soundtrack that barely gets in the way of storytelling, I believe that all-in-all, “ID: INVADED” was a rewarding watch for me. There is enough mystery to spice up each episode, although the overarching mystery could have been written better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Give it a watch should you have the time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Coding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CodingIndex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James</name></author><summary type="html">I’m a tech guy. I see sci-fi and psychological genre tags, I click. That was how I discovered this anime.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1889/105337.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1889/105337.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Re:Zero kara Hajimeru Isekai Seikatsu 2nd Season</title><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Re-Zero-kara-Hajimeru-Isekai-Seikatsu-2nd-Season/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Re:Zero kara Hajimeru Isekai Seikatsu 2nd Season" /><published>2020-12-05T23:45:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-12-05T23:45:00+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Re-Zero-kara-Hajimeru-Isekai-Seikatsu-2nd-Season</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Re-Zero-kara-Hajimeru-Isekai-Seikatsu-2nd-Season/">&lt;p&gt;This anime was recommended to me by a friend of mine, who is an avid fan of the series. He is one to usually drop anime when he is disinterested, and he has dropped &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; of anime. So, this must have been pretty good, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having watched the &lt;a href=&quot;https://myanimelist.net/anime/31240/Re_Zero_kara_Hajimeru_Isekai_Seikatsu&quot;&gt;first season&lt;/a&gt; a while back (in 2016), I’ve let the initial hype of Re:Zero die within me. What originally hooked me from the first season was how unique the main character’s struggle is, which is a result of the unique setting created for the story. Everything else, from the story’s conflicts, to how the main character overcomes them eventually is, well, bland, at most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;season-2&quot;&gt;Season 2&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a season that develops story elements and characters, finally introducing the “fabled” ones from Season 1, developing Beatrice and our most mysterious Roswaal. The season also gives us a glimpse into the inner workings of Subaru through a bunch of well-placed story-supported flashbacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, this is the one season that lacks the “punch” required for me to give it a higher rating - there is no significant event that would make me go around to recommend this to anybody. While it is true that a deeper lore is established between the characters through Subaru’s restarts, often changing who the suspected villain and ally groups are, the season lacks the defining moment that is the climax of a story arc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that this season is only a “Part 1” - there is still a “Part 2” coming soon. Hence, it might be fairer to judge the season as a whole after also watching Part 2 - for now, objectively judging the anime that is considered “complete” according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://myanimelist.net/anime/39587/Re_Zero_kara_Hajimeru_Isekai_Seikatsu_2nd_Season&quot;&gt;MyAnimeList&lt;/a&gt;, “Re:Zero kara Hajimeru Isekai Seikatsu 2nd Season” has been mighty underwhelming to watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; style=&quot;margin: 0 auto; display: block;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Ifl45L6TgLU&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;mt-3 text-center text-gray lh-condensed-ultra f6&quot;&gt;Season 2 Part 2 PV | Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ifl45L6TgLU&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&quot;&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cannot recommend a “must-watch” for “Re:Zero kara Hajimeru Isekai Seikatsu 2nd Season” - at least not in its current form. The key is Part 2 - if done right, Part 1 can be justified as having the necessary pre-requisite story, character and scene developments required for a impactful climax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Coding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CodingIndex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James</name></author><summary type="html">This anime was recommended to me by a friend of mine, who is an avid fan of the series. He is one to usually drop anime when he is disinterested, and he has dropped a lot of anime. So, this must have been pretty good, right?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1444/108005.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1444/108005.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Deca-Dence</title><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Deca-Dence/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Deca-Dence" /><published>2020-11-15T02:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-11-15T02:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Deca-Dence</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Deca-Dence/">&lt;p&gt;Color me surprised - this was quite a unique watch. Are you perhaps living in a simulation? Perhaps some sort of higher entity is controlling you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first watched Deca-Dence, I was expecting it to be something like &lt;a href=&quot;/anime/Shingeki-no-Kyojin/&quot;&gt;Shingeki no Kyojin&lt;/a&gt;, with all the post-apocalyptic hyping that the promotional video did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe style=&quot;display: block; margin: auto&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/OziblTliUbw&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center text-gray lh-condensed-ultra f6 mt-3&quot;&gt;Deca-Dence PV | Source &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OziblTliUbw&quot;&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-it-really-was&quot;&gt;What it really was&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This anime is a mix of existential crisis, epic giant battles, and the life of a girl in a post-apocalyptic world. For some, it is naught but a game; for others, it the matter of life and death. Would you put in your effort if you knew it didn’t matter in the end?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-actual-review&quot;&gt;The actual review&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t do my research beforehand, but I was surprised that Deca-Dence was animated by Nut, which is the same studio that animated &lt;a href=&quot;https://myanimelist.net/anime/32615/Youjo_Senki&quot;&gt;Youjo Senki&lt;/a&gt;. Perhaps the lack of distinction was due to how the characters are designed in Deca-Dence, but nevertheless, I couldn’t tell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless, the audiovisuals were good and complementary with one another - it is what I would expect of an anime made in 2020. Story-wise, I was surprised by the “setting twist” - which is a new term I shall coin for surprises similar to plot twists, but they happen in the settings instead of the plot (i.e. it wasn’t the progression of plot that surprised me, it was the scenario that surprised me).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even with the strange twist and turns around the scenario, the story remained shockingly consistent - in fact, the very last enemy had a clear backstory that was shown throughout the anime, with no need for flashbacks, or any story device explanations by any character in the anime. The methods for dealing with the enemies remained constant throughout, with variations only in the movements to deal damage, much like slicing the neck of a titan in Shingeki no Kyojin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Character development was evident throughout the entire story, making every episode feel fresh and exciting to watch. Battles were short, sweet and simple, so that the important plot elements can be introduced for plot progression purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, for an original anime created in 2020, Deca-Dence was quite a solid piece to watch. Give it a watch, I don’t think you’d regret it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Coding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CodingIndex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James</name></author><summary type="html">Color me surprised - this was quite a unique watch. Are you perhaps living in a simulation? Perhaps some sort of higher entity is controlling you?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1627/107552.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1627/107552.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Kimetsu no Yaiba Movie: Mugen Ressha-hen</title><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Kimetsu-no-Yaiba-Movie-Mugen-Ressha-hen/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kimetsu no Yaiba Movie: Mugen Ressha-hen" /><published>2020-11-15T01:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-11-15T01:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Kimetsu-no-Yaiba-Movie-Mugen-Ressha-hen</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Kimetsu-no-Yaiba-Movie-Mugen-Ressha-hen/">&lt;p&gt;The last time I reviewed Kimetsu no Yaiba, I was blown away by the audiovisuals. Of course I would be - it’s ufotable: famous for their unlimited budget works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I had to compare this movie to the previous installment of &lt;a href=&quot;/anime/Kimetsu-no-Yaiba/&quot;&gt;Kimetsu no Yaiba&lt;/a&gt;, it would be premium chocolate icing on well-baked sponge cake. In other words, the movie picked up the anime’s momentum perfectly, and preserved everything that made Kimetsu no Yaiba the one of the best hits in anime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;audiovisuals&quot;&gt;Audiovisuals&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As expected of ufotable, the visuals are stunning and communicates the story very well. Most scenes are well-complemented by the soundtrack, creating an ambiance to hook the user into the story. A testament to this is an emotional scene with Inosuke on set: ufotable was able to perfectly convey the emotions felt by a character who hides his face with a boar mask.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20201115_2.png&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 400px; width: 100%; margin: 0 auto; display: block;&quot; alt=&quot;Inosuke Hashibira&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center text-gray lh-condensed-ultra f6&quot;&gt;Inosuke Hashibira | Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://kimetsu-no-yaiba.fandom.com/wiki/Inosuke_Hashibira&quot;&gt;Fandom&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Real-life action movies usually have difficult-to-follow action scenes; they’re too fast paced for the eye to keep up. However, with the power of anime, slow-motion can be used to emphasize certain parts of the battle, which was done excellently in Kimetsu no Yaiba. Viewers are able to understand why certain actions performed by characters are considered impressive, or pivotal in a battle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that was done spectacularly were the dark scenes. During these scenes, the color adjusts to a grey-ish palette, which is a stark contrast to the usual bright palette used throughout the movie. This brings home the point that “oh, this is &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; serious”, which primes the viewers to brace for a high-impact conflict and resolve between the characters in the movie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CGI used in the movie is not too overwhelming, and does not overshadow the animation. CGI is mostly used in the movie whenever an object needs to have a large range of motion in a short period of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;story&quot;&gt;Story&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do not read the manga, so I judge the story entirely based on the anime and the movie. Personally, I believe that there are too many reaction scenes - there would be a fight at one moment, and at the next moment, Tanjiro would gasp, or exclaim “oh no!”, or look on with shock. This is a traditional shounen anime troupe to show the emotions of the main character as the story progresses, but I think the movie can do better to cut down on these scenes, as they were quite distracting to the actual events transpiring in the scene.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of actual events, some story elements to progress the plot were a little strange - it was not immediately clear how some characters managed to bypass the first conflict in the plot. It was also not clear why a direct solution the first conflict wouldn’t work, other than the main character going “I think solution X is a bad idea”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a shounen anime, the plotline was marginally predictable. However, I was surprised to find out that there were multiple climaxes to the movie - my surprise comes partly due to the PV only suggesting one major fight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe style=&quot;display:block; margin:auto&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/PrZ0O8Qp18s&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center text-gray lh-condensed-ultra f6 mt-3&quot;&gt;Kimetsu no Yaiba PV | Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PrZ0O8Qp18s&quot;&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, the movie remained mostly consistent with the facts we learned from the anime, which made the movie easy to follow. Another factor that contributed to understanding the movie was the good pacing of the movie - viewers were slowly introduced to the quirks of the enemy, before a fast-paced action sequence to defeat the enemy, followed by a short cooldown for all the viewers to catch their breath, followed by the display of quirks of the next enemy, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of character building, the movie develops both Tanjiro and Rengoku. In Tanjiro’s case, information we already knew was used to develop his character further, by combining both his tragic backstory and the enemy’s quirk, strengthening the viewer’s knowledge of Tanjiro’s values and morals. In Rengoku’s case, flashbacks were used to show the goals, motivations, and ethics of Rengoku. Through Rengoku and the enemies, Zenitsu and Inosuke both received minor developments in the form of a mentor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kimetsu no Yaiba Movie: Mugen Ressha-hen is a great movie. If you have been a fan of the Kimetsu no Yaiba anime you should watch the movie. If you are a fan of the Kimetsu no Yaiba manga, you should still watch the movie just for the audiovisuals. If you have not watched Kimetsu no Yaiba, check out &lt;a href=&quot;/anime/Kimetsu-no-Yaiba/&quot;&gt;my review&lt;/a&gt;, and try to give both the anime and the movie a watch too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy coding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CodingIndex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James</name></author><summary type="html">The last time I reviewed Kimetsu no Yaiba, I was blown away by the audiovisuals. Of course I would be - it’s ufotable: famous for their unlimited budget works.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1704/106947.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1704/106947.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Shokugeki no Souma: Gou no Sara</title><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Shokugeki-no-Souma-Gou-no-Sara/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Shokugeki no Souma: Gou no Sara" /><published>2020-10-07T06:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-10-07T06:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Shokugeki-no-Souma-Gou-no-Sara</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Shokugeki-no-Souma-Gou-no-Sara/">&lt;p&gt;And here we are at the season finale. It is always nostalgic to see the end of a series, especially for an anime as iconic as “Shokugeki no Souma”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike the previous seasons - our characters are closer to their culinary peaks than ever, being unbridled in strength compared to their peers. This is what we see in the first two episodes, as the new Elite Ten basically flexes their skills over the rest of the students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the key joys of watching Shokugeki no Souma is seeing Souma being the underdog and overcoming challenges head-on, but in this anime, that aspect of the anime is overshadowed by a overpowering villainous backstory, weird creative liberties to prepare meals, and rushed relationship developments with very cliched flashbacks to boot. Moreover, the “clothes explosion” staple found in every “Shokugeki no Souma” anime gets out of hand in this season - the “PG13 or older” rating is definitely off by at least 3 years; while I would like to illustrate what I mean, I’d rather my blog remain SFW.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;step-by-step-guide-to-figure-out-who-wins-a-round-of-shokugeki-in-shokugeki-no-souma-gou-no-sara&quot;&gt;Step-by-step guide to figure out who wins a round of Shokugeki in “Shokugeki no Souma: Gou no Sara”&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is he/she the last guy to present his/her dish?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If yes, he/she wins. If no, he/she loses.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;???&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Profit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The anime is extremely predictable; all you need to do is to keep the following facts in mind:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Souma is a main character, he cannot lose;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unless the opponent is Erina, then he may lose.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If the main antagonist is involved without Souma, the antagonist wins.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If the main antagonist faces off the main character, then the main character wins.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Historic capabilities and expected growth does not matter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BAM, you can now guess the outcomes of any plot presented to you in the anime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;who-matters&quot;&gt;Who matters?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When watching the anime, you can tell that certain scenes exist solely to develop one aspect of a plot device used later in the anime. For example, there was a scene used specifically to highlight how powerful the antagonist’s clique was - they spent 9/10 of the entire episode on each member of the clique, how good their culinary skills were, and how easily they were able to pass challenges that other chefs cannot. Then, out of a sudden, “ok so the three of you from Totsuki also pass kekw” - this makes the scene seem narrow in purpose, and difficult to find engaging if not for the crazy styles of cooking shown in the episode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Souma, being the main character, also gets incredibly lucky on many occasions; for example, in one scene, he was given two chances to pass a challenge. He fails the first time, and uses the &lt;strong&gt;same&lt;/strong&gt; philosophy to pass the second time. In another instance, Souma basically gambled on fried rice to win a competition round, while the opponent loses despite being far more experience with culinary skills from all over the world - either Souma reached godhood, which contradicts his losing streak with his seniors, or somehow “dedicating cooking to someone” meant an automatic boost in cooking skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The anime actually covers two concurrent events, but only explains that by hurling a large info-dump towards the viewer at the end of the season. This could have been executed better, as it seems to imply that only the main character’s stories really matter. In fairness, it gives the side-characters alibis so that the story can be concluded in whole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;villain-backstory--motivations&quot;&gt;Villain Backstory + Motivations&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I personally find the backstory and the (&lt;em&gt;true&lt;/em&gt;) motivations of the villain quite cliched. I also don’t think that it justifies how the villain managed to gain the amount of power he did, and why he is so driven. There are not enough story elements to piece together the villain’s culinary growth into what is effectively a deity in the food world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;relationship-development&quot;&gt;Relationship development&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was no relationship development to speak of for 24 episodes; then suddenly, in episode 25, families reunite, love is in the air, and everyone is proud to be in the same generation as Souma &lt;em&gt;despite&lt;/em&gt; Souma not even being present for any relationship development to take place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just, how exactly did they go from enemies to family?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;flashbacks&quot;&gt;Flashbacks&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is way too many flashbacks in this season. Granted, the characters can’t exactly go through the other methods of character development otherwise, given the nature and premise of the anime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Shokugeki no Souma: Gou no Sara” is the finale season of the entire “Shokugeki no Souma” series. Hence, I appreciate its existence as a series closer - if you have watched “Shokugeki no Souma” religiously up till &lt;a href=&quot;/anime/Shokugeki-no-Souma-Shin-no-Sara/&quot;&gt;“Shokugeki no Souma: Shin no Sara”&lt;/a&gt;, then you should watch this anime as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The anime is lacking in terms of story quality based on the points I discussed above - ranging from predictability, to poor methods of character building, to the sheer plot armor Souma possess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless, the series as a whole has been phenomenal!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Coding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CodingIndex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James</name></author><summary type="html">And here we are at the season finale. It is always nostalgic to see the end of a series, especially for an anime as iconic as “Shokugeki no Souma”.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1756/108000.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1756/108000.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>