<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/feed/anime.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-07-22T02:37:22+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/feed/anime.xml</id><title type="html">CodingIndex’s Random Shenanigans | Anime</title><subtitle>A (human) index that likes to code. Also drinks way too much coffee.</subtitle><author><name>James</name></author><entry><title type="html">Araburu Kisetsu no Otome-domo yo.</title><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Araburu-Kisetsu-no-Otome-Domo-Yo/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Araburu Kisetsu no Otome-domo yo." /><published>2019-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Araburu-Kisetsu-no-Otome-Domo-Yo</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Araburu-Kisetsu-no-Otome-Domo-Yo/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warning&lt;/strong&gt;: I watched this a month ago, and I don’t remember some parts of the anime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m surprised this anime got such a low rating, maybe the anime community generally dislikes highschool girls talking about ess-ee-ecks? This anime presents the struggles of literature club high school girls (and I guess males?) have against their teenage hormones in a realistic fashion. Some reject the entire idea of finding a partner, some choose alternatives, and some just go for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This anime illustrates the self-discovery journey of these highschoolers on discovering their sexuality, devise methods to tackle the pink-tinted lens they now see the world in, and generally just accepting it as a frequent biological impulse due to puberty. This anime is jam-packed full of drama, funny moments, and explores the idea of taboo relationships that will trigger a reflex to contact the police.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To top it off, the final drama will breathtakingly and nicely end the anime, making this anime one of the rare ones that concludes the series properly. You should give this anime a try, even if you don’t like the idea of ess-ee-ecks (you will also find out why I’m delibrately using this phrase).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Coding,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CodingIndex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James</name></author><summary type="html">Warning: I watched this a month ago, and I don’t remember some parts of the anime.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1256/101166.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1256/101166.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Haiyore! Nyaruko-san</title><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Haiyore-Nyaruko-san/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Haiyore! Nyaruko-san" /><published>2019-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Haiyore-Nyaruko-san</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Haiyore-Nyaruko-san/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warning&lt;/strong&gt;: Wrote this review 1 month after I viewed the anime. I have no idea what I’m talking about, but…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This anime is mediocre at everything. There’s nothing exciting, except maybe the first and last episode and some character’s lovecraftian origins. There’s nothing outstanding to speak about; usually, anime is different in one aspect or the other, but this particular one is just… normal?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know how to explain it, but if you got time to kill, and you really don’t want to be wow’d, I guess you can give this anime a shot. But with the plethora of other anime out there, I don’t think this anime stands out as being one you must watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Coding,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CodingIndex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James</name></author><summary type="html">Warning: Wrote this review 1 month after I viewed the anime. I have no idea what I’m talking about, but…</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/6/49081.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/6/49081.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Given</title><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Given/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Given" /><published>2019-10-28T00:02:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-10-28T00:02:00+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Given</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Given/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WARNING&lt;/strong&gt;: I wrote this review 1 month after watching it, so I probably have no idea what I’m talking about. Also, light spoilers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me first put up a big disclaimer that I don’t like Yaoi anime, not because I hate Yaoi, but because I just don’t like watching Yaoi anime. This is the first “Yaoi” anime I’ve watched, but I didn’t pick it up because it was Yaoi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the context: I had absolutely nothing to do one day, and wanted to watch anime. Given had an interesting description, with pretty good reviews. Seeing as I had absolutely nothing to do, I took the leap and broke my Yaoi cherry (please don’t use this sentence out of context).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ignoring the Yaoi parts, this was a solid anime about teenage boys doing band things, with enough character development to hook onto the viewer’s emotions. Mafuyu has a talent for angelic singing, but is unable to convey what he truly wants to express through his song - the story took the liberty of explaining his backstory by dropping hints here and there across the story, introducing drama, tension and confusion among the band members. At the climax of the story, he came to terms with it, during a concert no less. The emotional buildup that got released during the climax is also backed with the appropriate plot progression, and realistic character reactions, making the anime surprisingly relatable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To describe this anime in a phrase: a strange gem, in a otherwise gem field that is this season. :gem:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if you don’t like the Yaoi genre, do give it a shot. You may like it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Coding,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CodingIndex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James</name></author><summary type="html">WARNING: I wrote this review 1 month after watching it, so I probably have no idea what I’m talking about. Also, light spoilers.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1666/102238.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1666/102238.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Lord El-Melloi II Sei no Jikenbo: Rail Zeppelin Grace Note</title><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Lord-El-Melloi-II-Sei-No-Jikenbo-Rail-Zeppelin/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lord El-Melloi II Sei no Jikenbo: Rail Zeppelin Grace Note" /><published>2019-10-28T00:01:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-10-28T00:01:00+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Lord-El-Melloi-II-Sei-No-Jikenbo-Rail-Zeppelin</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Lord-El-Melloi-II-Sei-No-Jikenbo-Rail-Zeppelin/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warning&lt;/strong&gt;: I watched this 1.5 months ago, and am a diehard Fate fan. My reviews will definitely be skewed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;:tada::tada::tada: Finally, finally, finally! My boy finally gets his own anime. This anime is not for those not aware of some Fate lore, although you won’t need to know much to watch this anime. If you play &lt;a href=&quot;https://fate-go.us/&quot;&gt;Fate/Grand Order&lt;/a&gt;, you will see a familiar face here, one that you never thought you’ll see again :wink:.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Excitement aside, “Lord El-Melloi II Case Files: Rail Zeppelin” is fantastic; it follows a man with no talent in magecraft, but became a professor who teaches eccentric apprentices. He is also famous for solving several cases, with his favourite approach being the “whodunit” and “whydunit” approach (google them). In this anime, you follow Lord El-Melloi II as he solves multiple cases and interact with his apprentices, told through great story-teling with appropriate build-ups to exciting moments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do give it a go if you are a fan of the Fate franchise!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Coding,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CodingIndex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James</name></author><summary type="html">Warning: I watched this 1.5 months ago, and am a diehard Fate fan. My reviews will definitely be skewed.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1051/102394.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1051/102394.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Dungeon ni Deai wo Motomeru no wa Machigatteiru Darou ka II</title><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Dungeon-ni-Deai-wo-Motomeru-no-wa-Machigatteiru-Darou-ka-II/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dungeon ni Deai wo Motomeru no wa Machigatteiru Darou ka II" /><published>2019-10-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-10-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Dungeon-ni-Deai-wo-Motomeru-no-wa-Machigatteiru-Darou-ka-II</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Dungeon-ni-Deai-wo-Motomeru-no-wa-Machigatteiru-Darou-ka-II/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warning&lt;/strong&gt;: This review was written 1.5 months after I watched it, so I don’t remember most of what happened in the series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That being said though, I remember this being an anticipated Second season. This season wasn’t as exciting as the previous season - character development, with the exception of Lilith, was limited. To me, it seems more of a world-building and information-revelation season than a season meant for action. We do get to see some glimpses of Bell being a chad, but it was mainly “oh we got a new house”, “Lilith had such a backstory?” and “Hestia is in debt?” (i.e. stuff we already mostly knew).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get the feeling that this Season is meant to be like this, and the big “stuff” happens in Season 3, so watch this to get the relevant information you need to get hyped for the next season!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Coding,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CodingIndex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James</name></author><summary type="html">Warning: This review was written 1.5 months after I watched it, so I don’t remember most of what happened in the series.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1730/101329.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1730/101329.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Toaru Kagaku no Accelerator</title><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Toaru-Kagaku-no-Accelerator/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Toaru Kagaku no Accelerator" /><published>2019-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Toaru-Kagaku-no-Accelerator</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Toaru-Kagaku-no-Accelerator/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warning&lt;/strong&gt;: This review was writen 2 months after I watched it, but it doesn’t change the fact that it was pretty good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While “A Certain Magical Index III” was a flop, “A Certain Scientific Accelerator” made up for it. It didn’t do as much justice as “A Certain Scientific Railgun”, but nevertheless, at least it wasn’t as bad as “A Certain Magical Index III’. Many people were looking forward to “A Certain Scientific Accelerator” due to the popularity of Academy City’s Top 1 esper, but I was relatively impartial to the “epicness” of this character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To some extend, it was true - as a spinoff, “A Certain Scientific Accelerator” didn’t spur too much character development. Accelerator now relies on others to even use his ability, but it didn’t change him at a fundamental level, because he has always been the same, which is why despite being all-powerful, he still chose to save the little kid. In other words, Accelerator is still Accelerator, the foul mouth, arrogant and rude Top 1 esper of Academy City.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20191019_1.gif&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 400px; width: 100%; margin: 0 auto; display: block;&quot; alt=&quot;Accelerator being a villan&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center text-gray lh-condensed-ultra f6&quot;&gt;Accelerator | Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://gifer.com/en/AU8q&quot;&gt;Gifer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main thing that stood out of this anime is perhaps the story-telling, about Accelerator doing odd-jobs, saving the world, getting a disciple, et. cetera. Accelerator might not have grown much as a character, but it is nevertheless enjoyable to see him do work and how he approaches obstacles, which futhur reinforces the “yep, that’s Accelerator” ideology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This also means the anime would be meaningless for the people who did not follow the “A Certain Magical Index” series - in which case, it might be a good idea to start there, before watching the spinoffs. Spinoffs can only exist thanks to the main storyline, so to understand what makes the spinoffs good/bad, one needs to have watched the main series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if you’ve watched “A Certain Magical Index” up to Season 3, and have binged through “A Certain Scientific Railgun” like a true Misaka fan (I am), then you may find “A Certain Scientific Accelerator” enjoyable; else, it may not be your cup of tea :coffee:.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Coding,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CodingIndex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James</name></author><summary type="html">Warning: This review was writen 2 months after I watched it, but it doesn’t change the fact that it was pretty good.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1160/99995.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1160/99995.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Demon Slayer: Kimetsu no Yaiba</title><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Kimetsu-no-Yaiba/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Demon Slayer: Kimetsu no Yaiba" /><published>2019-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Kimetsu-no-Yaiba</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Kimetsu-no-Yaiba/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warning&lt;/strong&gt;: This review was written 2 months after I watched it, but dude this thing is :bomb:. Also, don’t play any of the videos in this post if you don’t want to be spoiled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Demon Slayer is a Shounen anime that took the internet by storm, and for good reason; it’s a piece of art. I’ve said this in previous reviews, but I am not a huge fan of Shounen anime, so why am I singing such high praises? For me, it’s two main things: (i) audiovisual mastery and (ii) hype towards any fight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s talk about audiovisual mastery. There is a studio that puts out unlimited money towards making their animations eye-candy to feast upon: that is ufotable. The visuals for this anime is otherworldly and extremely enjoyable to watch. Just look at this animation sequence from the famous episode 19 of the anime:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20191015_1.gif&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 400px; width: 100%; margin: 0 auto; display: block;&quot; alt=&quot;Tanjiro Hinokami Kagura&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center text-gray lh-condensed-ultra f6&quot;&gt;Tanjiro's Fire Breathing Scene | Credit: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tumblr.com/tagged/kimetsu-no-yaiba-spoilers&quot;&gt;Tumblr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The background music playing for this scene is astonishingly fitting, with the right transitions playing at the right frame - seriously, if you have no idea what I’m talking about, just watch (and hear) this short clip from Demon Slayer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/brCe7D0vLVE&quot; style=&quot;display:block; margin:auto&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, there is the buildup towards the “ultimate action” in a fight. If you ask me, the core of any Shounen fight is the ultimate deciding move - the move where the fight is at it’s climax, and the winner/loser can be easily discerned. Demon Slayer: Kimetsu no Yaiba does this exceptoinally well, especially for fights involving Zenitsu; the OST for him is absolutely on point, and you can feel it in your soul when he unleashes an epic move. If you’ve already watched the show, you would know what I mean, just look at this clip:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ce6dhqGWdrA&quot; style=&quot;display:block; margin:auto&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, if you haven’t watched Demon Slayer: Kimetsu no Yaiba yet, you should definitely do it. It’s worth the hype :+1:.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Coding,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CodingIndex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James</name></author><summary type="html">Warning: This review was written 2 months after I watched it, but dude this thing is :bomb:. Also, don’t play any of the videos in this post if you don’t want to be spoiled.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1286/99889.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1286/99889.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Boku no Hero Academia</title><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Boku-No-Hero-Academia/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Boku no Hero Academia" /><published>2019-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Boku-No-Hero-Academia</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Boku-No-Hero-Academia/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warning&lt;/strong&gt;: This reviews Season 1 thorugh Season 3. This review was written 2 months after I watched it, so I don’t remember half of what happened in the series, although I can generally tell you why it’s pretty good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have never been a die-hard fan of pure shounen shows - they’re usually my “side-quest” anime whenever I stockpile anime to watch. Boku no Hero Academia hasn’t changed my mind about how I view shounen show, but it was quite enjoyable to watch. It follows a boy named “Midoriya”, who wants to be a hero but lacks the ability to do so, as he was born unlike others with natural quirks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I would like to say hard work and perseverance paid off and he finally was able to become a hero, I would argue it is not entirely true - it’s like Rikkudo Senin granting Naruto his Six Paths power. Sure, Naruto worked hard to get to where he was before the power boost, but it does not change the fact that he simply “got” a power boost as a gift from someone else. Midoriya in Boku no Hero Academia gains a power boost on similar terms, making it difficult to comprehend and resonate with as a character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence, while this anime is enjoyable for the fights, and the characte development, the base of the characters are difficult to resonate with, making it difficult to feel emotional about the anime. But, well, it’s a shounen show, so you should enjoy it like a shounen show. Don’t expect too much, just enjoy it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Coding,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CodingIndex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James</name></author><summary type="html">Warning: This reviews Season 1 thorugh Season 3. This review was written 2 months after I watched it, so I don’t remember half of what happened in the series, although I can generally tell you why it’s pretty good.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/10/78745.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/10/78745.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Rising of the Shield Hero</title><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/The-Rising-of-the-Shield-Hero/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Rising of the Shield Hero" /><published>2019-09-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/anime/The-Rising-of-the-Shield-Hero</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/The-Rising-of-the-Shield-Hero/">&lt;p&gt;It has been a while since I last reviewed an anime, but it doesn’t mean I’ve stopped watching them. I just simply put them off, becase I’m lazy :stuck_out_tongue_winking_eye:. As such, I might not produce a “good” review, just one that is good enough to convince you whether you should watch it, or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year (2019) is the year of Isekai. Animation studios seem to churn out nothing but Isekai anime, almost as if testing the response of anime fans; and you know what, I’m perfectly okay with that. Personally, I find Isekai a great escape from real life, because all the rules that are normally imposed on the world are broken in an instant, and that provides a massive opportunity for world &amp;amp; character development. For the anime that do this well, I’ll gleefully watch with no complains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Rising of the Shield Hero was one such anime. Instead of starting the Isekai with a ridiculously overpowered main character, which subsequently causes all the other characters to rely on the main character, “The Rising of the Shield Hero” shows the other side of human interaction - the one where the reliance on others is crucial to the survival and willpower to live as a human being.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This makes the main character very relatable, while still maintaining the fantasy setting introduced by the Isekai. In real life, you’d probably have to rely on somebody to give you the meaning to live - without that crucial pillar, life is probably not worth living. Following the main character who starts off rock bottom, you can see him change himself and the world around him as he encounters people who slowly becomes his pillar of life, and going absolutely mental without them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, an anime is not only about relatable characters and great character &amp;amp; world development. The other rating criteria are fulfilled properly too; the story was pretty fantastic, with reasonable climaxes and resolutions, and get this: the responses actually makes sense. Enemies don’t suddenly become friends, and vice-versa - the interaction was honestly quite human. Visuals are really pleasing, and synchronizes well with the story to bring out emotions (like rage and sorrow) from the viewers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And man, can I just - THE OST IS SO GOOD! My man &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kevinpenkin?lang=en&quot;&gt;Kevin Penkin&lt;/a&gt;, who also created the OST for Made in Abyss (one of my favourites) is back at it again dropping the sick beats :musical_note:. Anime, to me, will not be complete without godly soundtrack - and this nailed it. The soundtrack was well synchronized with the visuals, and empowered the story to convey emotions, be it anger, sadness, relief, happiness, melancholy, et cetera.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, I can’t really fault the series for anything; I felt that everything I cared about for anime was in-place. If you are still not convinced to watch it yet, I suggest that you do it for the OST, then slowly get sublimated by the story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welp, on to the next review.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Coding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CodingIndex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James</name></author><summary type="html">It has been a while since I last reviewed an anime, but it doesn’t mean I’ve stopped watching them. I just simply put them off, becase I’m lazy :stuck_out_tongue_winking_eye:. As such, I might not produce a “good” review, just one that is good enough to convince you whether you should watch it, or not.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1490/101365.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1490/101365.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Tenki no Ko</title><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Tenki-no-Ko/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tenki no Ko" /><published>2019-09-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Tenki-no-Ko</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Tenki-no-Ko/">&lt;p&gt;Also known as “Weathering with You”, which came out in my local cinema a few days ago. This is also the reason why I’ve been clearing my backlog of animes to review so quickly (and sloppily).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, where to start…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t read my review for &lt;a href=&quot;/anime/Kimi-No-Nawa/&quot;&gt;Kimi no Na wa.&lt;/a&gt;, then you should read it first. “Kimi no Na wa.” absolutely destroyed box office records, being one of the best, if not the best, work of Makoto Shinkai. “Kimi no Na wa.” was able to touch millions of hearts, being the role model of character building, world development and story telling for all of anime, even though it was a movie. “Kimi no Na wa.” was also the anime that resparked my dormant emotions for the “Romance” and “Drama” genre; both of which I have absolutely no interest in normally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beautiful visuals, amazing soundtracks, appropriate timing for events, and honestly breathtaking emotional moments, they all add up together to make a hearty soup of feels that just punches through your guts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that pretext out of the way, let’s begin by asking a question: do you like rain?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20190914_1.gif&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 400px; width: 100%; margin: 0 auto; display: block;&quot; alt=&quot;Rain GIF from Weathering With You&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center text-gray lh-condensed-ultra f6&quot;&gt;Do you like rain? | Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://weheartit.com/entry/329650401&quot;&gt;WeHeartIt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;rain&quot;&gt;Rain&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some people, they might like it; the relaxing sounds of water droplets hitting the ground, combined with the cooling effect that rain has on the environment; it makes urban cities with their flashy LEDs, traffic lights, and car headlights more vibrant and breathtaking. Some children enjoy rain because they get to play with water, some teenagers enjoy it because it lets them sleep longer, and some adults enjoy it because it gives them a break from hectic life to think about, well, life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rain is a small wonder of the planet, able to bring about emotions unconsciously, like depression, anxiety, and sadness, giving us time to think and reflect of our actions for the week. It is a temporary seclusion from our everyday lives, and a mechanism automatically triggered by mother nature, almost as if to coax us into reflection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rain is beautiful; visually and audibly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20190914_2.gif&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 400px; width: 100%; margin: 0 auto; display: block;&quot; alt=&quot;Sunrise GIF&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center text-gray lh-condensed-ultra f6&quot;&gt;Maybe you like the sun instead? | Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://tenor.com/view/anime-sunrise-morning-sunset-gif-12714208&quot;&gt;Tenor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some other people, they hate the rain; it’s suffocating and restrictive, and they would much prefer to have a sunny day to air their laundry, and play in the park. Perhaps their profession relies on the sun to be out; or maybe they enjoy being in the heat, exercising and playing their heart away. It gives humans the feeling of being in society when we do something in the heat together; the sun literally and figuratively brightens up the mood and atmosphere of any event, and conveys emotions like joy and excitement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walking in the park with the sun out paints a beautiful picture, wonderous and almost other-worldly. Imagine the children laughing as they play under the sun, the teenagers hanging out with one another, and adults going about their lives, busy with work that as a collective, pushes humanity forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sun is a welcome sight; and it powers our society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the rain to you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;weathering-with-you&quot;&gt;Weathering with You&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you could control the weather, which will you choose? Sunny, or rainy? Would you even choose to control the weather?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The weather works in mysterious ways. Even with all of our technology, our predictions for weather is only informative at best; “Weathering with You” leverages that unknown, and amplifies it a notch; to a story that can be parsed and understood by us, and create an engaging narrative that only we can understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The setting of “Weathering with You” lies in the city of Tokyo, which can really be replaced with any other city in the world - any urban environment where the jobs are the only way to survive. Cities like these are depressing and gloomy, where everyone is focused on their work, unaware of the pleasures of life as our ancestors know it; after all, the secret to life has been changed from around a few hundred years ago. Now, it’s all about working to get money to enjoy momentary pleasures before going back to the same routine everyday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As such, being a youth is the only long-term escape to such a boring life - it’s kind of similar to the setting of “Kimi no Na Wa.”. However, the main characters of this movie is far from being ordinary; as you will see when you watch it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A love story that can only occur in a harsh urban environment, “Weathering with You” does an excellent job at setting the scene. What about the story itself?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thinking about it in hindsight, the story was quite interesting; plot devices were added for a reason, and all of them come into full effect later on. It was really a spectacular thing to see all the pieces falling into place during the climax, and I believe it touched everyone in the same movie theatre as me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the pacing was kind of off - things happen so quickly that sometimes, it was difficult to catch what was going on. Characters progressed their thoughts and relationships really quickly, which doesn’t give us enough time to synchronize ourselves with the characters; in other words, the actions of the characters didn’t resonate well with the audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be frank, the impact that “Kimi no Na wa.” left on the world probably made this anime less enticing to react to; the emotions didn’t get conveyed to the audience well, and some of the actions the characters take were rashful. This &lt;a href=&quot;https://myanimelist.net/reviews.php?id=314251&quot;&gt;review&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;anime_feels&lt;/code&gt; summarizes this very well:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No one laughed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No one cried&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No one cheered or got excited&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No one clapped at the end&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;anime_feels&lt;/code&gt; also bring up a good point about the characters; they’re unique, which makes them difficult to relate to. Combining this with the fast-paced plot really throws me off balance, which was a shame, really. Perhaps it was the time constraints of the movie, but if this story was repaced differently, I feel like it could have helped in stabbing more people in the heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, while the story was good, the impact was not there; at least not as prominent as “Kimi no Na Wa.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;visuals-and-sound&quot;&gt;Visuals and Sound&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The visuals were fantastic. The first few seconds of the movie zooms out on a curtain, and it was the most well-drawn curtain I’ve ever seen in my life; I would buy that curtain if it was real. The sound is top-notch; almost on par with “Kimi no Na Wa.”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the pacing of the movie was better, the visual and sound would have impacted me a lot longer, so I don’t have to search YouTube for the OST; but alas, it was unavoidable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;should-i-watch-it&quot;&gt;Should I watch it?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes. It’s not going to be as great as “Kimi no Na Wa.”, but it’s still quite exemplary - leaving an impact can almost be attributed to production luck; and this one didn’t hit it. There’s no fixed formula to make something impactful, and “Tenki no Ko” proved it by following the same formula as “Kimi no Na Wa.”, achieving no success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anime like this, which are targetted to young audiences (like me :wink:) sometimes do trigger some thoughts - such as the question about rain above. If anything, this anime taught me that the smallest pleasures can lead to overall happiness; sometimes living in an urban city as dull and depressing as Tokyo will require the person to be resilient; and that can come from many sources, one of them being the ability to enjoy the simplest pleasures in life - be it to enjoy the weather, warm food, or a cold beverage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this mindless world, the only way to survive is either to be resilient enough, or await death. The act of choosing one path will help configure the other options that will help a person survive to the bitter end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was half an essay, and half an anime review. The bottom line is, you should watch it, but don’t expect too much; I gave it a high rating because it got me thinking about my own life, alongside the beautiful visuals and sound.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This concludes the review spam. Enjoy your anime!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Coding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CodingIndex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James</name></author><summary type="html">Also known as “Weathering with You”, which came out in my local cinema a few days ago. This is also the reason why I’ve been clearing my backlog of animes to review so quickly (and sloppily).</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1880/101146.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1880/101146.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>