<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/feed/anime.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-06-26T05:30:17+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/feed/anime.xml</id><title type="html">CodingIndex’s Random Shenanigans | Anime</title><subtitle>A (human) index that likes to code. Also drinks way too much coffee.</subtitle><author><name>James</name></author><entry><title type="html">Horimiya</title><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Horimiya/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Horimiya" /><published>2021-04-25T08:42:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-04-25T08:42:00+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Horimiya</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Horimiya/">&lt;p&gt;After thoroughly enjoying &lt;a href=&quot;/anime/Yahari-Ore-no-Seishun-Love-Comedy-wa-Machigatteiru/&quot;&gt;Oregairu&lt;/a&gt;, I looked for an anime that could replace the empty hole in my heart left by the anime. I daresay that Horimiya is one of the best in the romance-highschool anime genre that has ever been aired on TV.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve repeated this many times over in other reviews, but I do not typically watch romance anime; they’re usually too sappy, or too ecchi for me. However, I have been eyeing Horimiya for a while, especially after receiving recommendations to give it a shot by the online community. For the longest time, I’ve never been able to find an anime I liked enough to also binge the manga.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;synopsis&quot;&gt;Synopsis&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20210425_2.png&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 400px; width: 100%; margin: 0 auto; display: block;&quot; alt=&quot;Horimiya Feature Art&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center text-gray lh-condensed-ultra f6&quot;&gt;Horimiya | Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://butwhythopodcast.com/2021/01/10/review-horimiya-episode-1-a-tiny-happenstance/&quot;&gt;But why though?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Horimiya is an anime that centers around Hori and Miyamura, two starkly contrasting characters who were able to meet due to a certain incident. In no other circumstances would they have met; Hori is an honors student who was popular and a beauty, while Miyamura was a quiet loner who was distant to everyone in class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the certain incident, both Hori and Miyamura stumbled across sides of their characters concealed from the outside world, something none of them have done before; Miyamura has many piercings and tattoos on his body, while Hori was always busy thanks to her housework - these two grew closer to each other as they spent more time with their true selves, leading to interesting and heartwarming events to transpire within the anime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;opening&quot;&gt;Opening&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I loved the opening for Horimiya - it has some kind of tranquility that I cannot really explain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe style=&quot;display: block; margin: 0 auto;&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/haJwpsJ4Uj4&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center text-gray lh-condensed-ultra f6 mt-3&quot;&gt;Yoh Kamiyama - Irokosui | Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=haJwpsJ4Uj4&quot;&gt;Melodic Star @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Horimiya skips all the fluff in between getting to know each other, to actually being in a relationship within two episodes; this seems to be a deliberate choice, given how unlikely it is to maintain the atmosphere in the scenes otherwise. At first, this felt too rushed; however, I later understood that the relationship has to exist to bring out certain elements that the author is trying to convey - for instance, questioning the stability of the relationship, how it feels to have a 5 day no-interaction gap from the significant other, how does jealousy feel, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;human-like-issues-human-like-solutions&quot;&gt;Human-like issues, Human-like solutions&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing about Horimiya is how natural the individuals felt with their quirks, and how that affects the relationships. For instance, Miyamura is highly self-conscious about his piercings and tattoos, and tries his hardest not to reveal them; this causes him to dress heavily no matter how warm the whether is, which many people worriedly remarks on until it becomes “just a Miyamura thing”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20210425_3.jpg&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 400px; width: 100%; margin: 0 auto; display: block;&quot; alt=&quot;Miyamura's Tattoos&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center text-gray lh-condensed-ultra f6&quot;&gt;Miyamura's Tattoos | Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pinterest.com/pin/521432463113179769/&quot;&gt;Pinterest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While employing reasonable solutions to problems, Horimiya is able to somehow turn that into comedy, making it one of the only “comedic” anime that I can truly relate to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;differences-to-manga&quot;&gt;Differences to Manga&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the most part, Horimiya loyally follows the manga. There are some dropped bits here and there, probably to fit the ending of the manga within the (short) timeline of 12 episodes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest dropped events in Horimiya is the sports festival, which will hopefully air in the form of an OVA sometime in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;side-characters&quot;&gt;Side-characters&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Horimiya isn’t just about a romance between two characters; it is also about the two characters’ interaction with the other people around them. The cast of side-characters helps the audience take a breather to observe a fresh interaction apart from those by Hori and Miyamura, which develops the story, context and scenario. The results of these interactions are then used as a plot device to strengthen a concept later on down the road, or highlight the emotions of a particular scene; a good example of this would be the last episode of Horimiya.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20210425_4.jpg&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 400px; width: 100%; margin: 0 auto; display: block;&quot; alt=&quot;Tooru and his interaction with Yui &amp;amp; Sakura&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center text-gray lh-condensed-ultra f6&quot;&gt;Tooru, Yui &amp;amp; Sakura | Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://rabujoi.wordpress.com/tag/haircut/&quot;&gt;Rabujoi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;ending&quot;&gt;Ending&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can be said that the whole series is slowly building up towards the ending of Horimiya; unlike other romance anime, where the series ends after the main character engages one of the possible heroines, Horimiya is about building a rock-solid relationship from interest to engagement. From all the little details in each episode, to all the actions performed by the characters, we see and understand how and why the ending is achieved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Horimiya is something I enjoyed while highly fatigued; yet, it was able to lift my mood, and conveyed emotions in a way I can only hope to one day feel in my life. Of all the romance-highschool-comedy anime I’ve ever watched, I think Horimiya tops them all, including over &lt;a href=&quot;https://myanimelist.net/anime/37450/Seishun_Buta_Yarou_wa_Bunny_Girl_Senpai_no_Yume_wo_Minai&quot;&gt;Bunny Girl Senpai&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is probably likely never going to be an anime that can blow my expectations out of the water - after I watched the first few episodes, I realized that I was craving to watch the next episode. After also reading the manga, I daresay that Horimiya is the :gem: of Winter 2021.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This must go on top of your to-watch list; I highly encourage you to give Horimiya a watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Coding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CodingIndex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James</name></author><summary type="html">After thoroughly enjoying Oregairu, I looked for an anime that could replace the empty hole in my heart left by the anime. I daresay that Horimiya is one of the best in the romance-highschool anime genre that has ever been aired on TV.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1791/110336.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1791/110336.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Re:Zero kara Hajimeru Isekai Seikatsu 2nd Season</title><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Re-Zero-kara-Hajimeru-Isekai-Seikatsu-2nd-Season/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Re:Zero kara Hajimeru Isekai Seikatsu 2nd Season" /><published>2021-04-25T07:37:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-04-25T07:37:00+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Re-Zero-kara-Hajimeru-Isekai-Seikatsu-2nd-Season</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Re-Zero-kara-Hajimeru-Isekai-Seikatsu-2nd-Season/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EDIT&lt;/strong&gt;: Includes Part 2. This anime was recommended to me by a friend of mine, who is an avid fan of the series. He is one to usually drop anime when he is disinterested, and he has dropped &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; of anime. So, this must have been pretty good, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having watched the &lt;a href=&quot;https://myanimelist.net/anime/31240/Re_Zero_kara_Hajimeru_Isekai_Seikatsu&quot;&gt;first season&lt;/a&gt; a while back (in 2016), I’ve let the initial hype of Re:Zero die within me. What originally hooked me from the first season was how unique the main character’s struggle is, which is a result of the unique setting created for the story. Everything else, from the story’s conflicts, to how the main character overcomes them eventually is, well, bland, at most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;season-2&quot;&gt;Season 2&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a season that develops story elements and characters, finally introducing the “fabled” ones from Season 1, developing Beatrice and our most mysterious Roswaal. The season also gives us a glimpse into the inner workings of Subaru through a bunch of well-placed story-supported flashbacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, this is the one season that lacks the “punch” required for me to give it a higher rating - there is no significant event that would make me go around to recommend this to anybody. While it is true that a deeper lore is established between the characters through Subaru’s restarts, often changing who the suspected villain and ally groups are, the season lacks the defining moment that is the climax of a story arc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that this season is only a “Part 1” - there is still a “Part 2” coming soon. Hence, it might be fairer to judge the season as a whole after also watching Part 2 - for now, objectively judging the anime that is considered “complete” according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://myanimelist.net/anime/39587/Re_Zero_kara_Hajimeru_Isekai_Seikatsu_2nd_Season&quot;&gt;MyAnimeList&lt;/a&gt;, “Re:Zero kara Hajimeru Isekai Seikatsu 2nd Season” has been mighty underwhelming to watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; style=&quot;margin: 0 auto; display: block;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Ifl45L6TgLU&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;mt-3 text-center text-gray lh-condensed-ultra f6&quot;&gt;Season 2 Part 2 PV | Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ifl45L6TgLU&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&quot;&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;update-season-2-part-2&quot;&gt;Update: Season 2 Part 2&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part 2 fixed some issues I had with Part 1 - I henceforth dub this part the “answerer of all questions”, in theme with Echidna’s witch power. The conflict in the last season involving Beatrice finally gets resolved within this Part. Many questions were also answered, including Roswaal’s involvement, Beatrice’s connection to Roswaal through the gospel, and why the whole conflict was even happening in the first place. If Season 2 Part 1 was the “question enticer” of Season 2, then Season 2 Part 2 is the best possible pairing to conclude the season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe that Re:Zero is closing on the end of the whole series post-Season 2; let’s see where it takes us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cannot recommend a “must-watch” for “Re:Zero kara Hajimeru Isekai Seikatsu 2nd Season” - at least not in its current form. The key is Part 2 - if done right, Part 1 can be justified as having the necessary pre-requisite story, character and scene developments required for a impactful climax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;EDIT: While I still think “Re:Zero kara Hajimeru Isekai Seikatsu 2nd Season” isn’t a must watch, I believe that it deserves to have a higher priority in your bucket list compared to an anime like &lt;a href=&quot;/anime/Jujutsu-Kaisen/&quot;&gt;Jujutsu Kaisen&lt;/a&gt; within Winter 2021. Take that recommendation however you will!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Coding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CodingIndex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James</name></author><summary type="html">EDIT: Includes Part 2. This anime was recommended to me by a friend of mine, who is an avid fan of the series. He is one to usually drop anime when he is disinterested, and he has dropped a lot of anime. So, this must have been pretty good, right?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1444/108005.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1444/108005.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Jujutsu Kaisen</title><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Jujutsu-Kaisen/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jujutsu Kaisen" /><published>2021-04-25T07:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-04-25T07:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Jujutsu-Kaisen</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Jujutsu-Kaisen/">&lt;p&gt;A Shounen anime from Autumn 2021, which finally finished airing alongside Winter 2021 anime. Jujutsu Kaisen fills most of the roles practically mandated by most Shounen anime: the mentor, the rival, the girl and the steadfast and slightly airheaded main character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite being the most generic anime ever with the most generic setting ever, making it seem like a clone of Naruto than anything else, the anime is somehow popular enough to receive one of the highest ratings in this season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I’m really confused as to why; but:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;audiovisuals&quot;&gt;Audiovisuals&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going to put this section first because it’s important. &lt;strong&gt;Have you seen the ED for Jujutsu Kaisen?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe style=&quot;margin: 0 auto; display: block;&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/AWEm4tA2hMc&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;mt-3 text-center text-gray lh-condensed-ultra f6&quot;&gt;Jujutsu Kaisen ED | Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AWEm4tA2hMc&quot;&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This thing slaps; this is an ED that makes you forget that the anime leaves cliffhangers that make you itch for more. Apart from the opening and the ending, the visuals didn’t particularly stand out too much otherwise; which is good given that most of the action happens in the visuals and story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;story&quot;&gt;Story&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being a shounen anime, the story isn’t particularly interesting compared to other anime within the same genre. That being said, this generic shounen anime is a good model for future anime to follow; being in an over-saturated genre, keeping viewer’s interest is an increasingly difficult endeavour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What this anime does well is pacing and consistency: training arcs feel reasonable, the speed at which the characters move are consistent with their mentioned abilities, and powers are explained in an easy to understand manner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there are many part of the stories where I subconsciously compare the anime to Naruto, due to how similar the characters are. For instance, Itadori can be compared to Naruto: they both rush into situations without much thought, are natural airheads and have a “beast” within them with a crazy amount of power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20210425_1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 800px; width: 100%; margin: 0 auto; display: block;&quot; alt=&quot;Jujutsu Characters&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center text-gray lh-condensed-ultra f6&quot;&gt;Jujutsu Characters | Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.superdelivery.com/en/r/pd_p/9050235/&quot;&gt;SuperDelivery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gojou Satoru looks like Kakashi, has a similar aloof attitude to things, quite well-known in their respective worlds, and serves as a overseer for the “beast” lurking in Itadori/Naruto. While some characters are generic, there are also new personalities added into the mix; for example, there is Panda who is not a human, Toge who has unique speech due to his ability circumstance, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A mix of “known” characters alongside “fresh” ones gives the story some level of engagement that keeps the viewers interested in the characters’ interactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This season introduces a large portion of the world, its context, and their standards. From explaining the tiers of curses to how they can be dispel, to the different levels of Jujutsu Sorcerers and how they are paired to a situation, to the constraint of manpower, a ton of information is being pumped to the users at a time. Luckily, the anime does this well - information is presented in tidbits, only when they are required to explain situations within the scene.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jujutsu Kaisen is a generic shounen anime that is well-executed and interesting to watch. However, this season of anime has a bunch of other anime more worth your time; hence, you should only watch Jujutsu Kaisen during a content drought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Coding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CodingIndex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James</name></author><summary type="html">A Shounen anime from Autumn 2021, which finally finished airing alongside Winter 2021 anime. Jujutsu Kaisen fills most of the roles practically mandated by most Shounen anime: the mentor, the rival, the girl and the steadfast and slightly airheaded main character.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1171/109222.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1171/109222.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Jaku-Chara Tomozaki-kun</title><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Jaku-Chara-Tomozaki-kun/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jaku-Chara Tomozaki-kun" /><published>2021-04-18T10:07:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-04-18T10:07:00+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Jaku-Chara-Tomozaki-kun</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Jaku-Chara-Tomozaki-kun/">&lt;p&gt;Right, another romance anime. I promise that I still love Psychological anime, but recently, I’ve started to consume romance high-school anime like crazy, thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;/anime/Yahari-Ore-no-Seishun-Love-Comedy-wa-Machigatteiru/&quot;&gt;Oregairu&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/anime/Horimiya/&quot;&gt;Horimiya&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;story&quot;&gt;Story&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the concept of gaming as a base, Jaku-Chara Tomozaki-kun follows Tomozaki-kun, a god at a brawl game, as he plays through the game of life as the lowest-possible-tier character. The game of life requires social interaction, which many people, including myself, is completely inept at wielding competently; for Tomozaki-kun, who has no friends, and no life outside of gaming, social interaction is a skill he kept at level 0 since he was born.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After an offline meeting with NO-NAME, they discover that they come from the same school, and the god player of the brawl game is a loser in real life. Determined to change this, both Tomozaki and Aoi decided to try and raise Tomozaki’s level, at least to the level where he can get a girlfriend by the end of summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An interesting concept aside, I personally believe that chemistry is important when trying to pair ideas together. Gaming + romance is something that has been explored to death in other forms, such as the case in &lt;a href=&quot;https://myanimelist.net/anime/8525/Kami_nomi_zo_Shiru_Sekai&quot;&gt;The World God Only Knows&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://myanimelist.net/anime/21877/High_Score_Girl&quot;&gt;High Score Girl&lt;/a&gt;. Hence, I couldn’t help but feel like the combination has become closer to being cliché than novel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The anime is systematic in ensuring its viewers understand the story flow within the first two episodes; Aoi writes goals that Tomozaki should try and achieve before any conflict could even arise in the story, and comes back to this board regularly to check on Tomozaki’s progress. This creates a clear path for the storyline that is difficult to deviate from, which makes some conversations within the story quite awkward and forced, albeit that might be the writer’s goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later on in the story, Tomozaki breaks out of these systematic goals and decides to just be himself for a while, restoring a factor of unpredictability that all anime should have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20210418_10.jpg&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 400px; width: 100%; margin: 0 auto; display: block;&quot; alt=&quot;Characters in Jaku-Chara Tomozaki-kun&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center text-gray lh-condensed-ultra f6&quot;&gt;Characters in Jaku-Chara Tomozaki-kun | Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/myanimelist/status/1324577646349529088&quot;&gt;Tiwitter @myanimelist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jaku-Chara Tomozaki-kun is, at the moment, an incomplete story; by observing how the plot is progressing, there is probably a whole deal more that the story authors are planning, such that “multiple routes” become available eventually. Abducting backwards, this means that the plot progression is slow, which is a norm for high school romance anime where the main protagonist is a social recluse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, viewing the beginnings of a romance anime is still relatively enjoyable, despite some portions of the anime being difficult to watch due to how stale or awkward they were - I hope this is all just part of the setup towards something greater in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;character-development&quot;&gt;Character Development&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The series is at the beginning, so there is not much character development among all the characters. The two exceptions to this rule would be Tomozaki himself, and Nanami - both of which grew significantly within this first season. Tomozaki is an obvious case, considering the entire anime surrounds him stepping out of his comfort zone to try out the game of life, while Nanami, on the other hand, gets over her inferiority complex as she tries to fight against her rival.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Character development is an important aspect in an anime with little to no world-building, and a almost-stagnant plot progression, as it is the only factor that engages the viewers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;audiovisuals&quot;&gt;Audiovisuals&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not going to lie, the main character looks a lot like me: ugly and a sore sight no matter where he goes. Otherwise, the visuals are pretty, and the audio doesn’t get in the way; I’d say that’s good enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the moment, Jaku-Chara Tomozaki-kun is a mediocre anime. Perhaps it’ll get better as new seasons are released, but it shouldn’t be at the top of your to-watch list, unless that list is empty. I’ll look out for what the next season (if any) brings!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Coding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CodingIndex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James</name></author><summary type="html">Right, another romance anime. I promise that I still love Psychological anime, but recently, I’ve started to consume romance high-school anime like crazy, thanks to Oregairu and Horimiya.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1120/109232.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1120/109232.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Wonder Egg Priority</title><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Wonder-Egg-Priority/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wonder Egg Priority" /><published>2021-04-18T09:39:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-04-18T09:39:00+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Wonder-Egg-Priority</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Wonder-Egg-Priority/">&lt;p&gt;As a self-proclaimed professional psychological anime critic, I looked forward to watching Wonder Egg Priority, especially after the flop that was &lt;a href=&quot;/anime/The-Promised-Neverland-Season-2/&quot;&gt;The Promised Neverland Season 2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And you know what, Wonder Egg Priority was wonderful. An anime that explores the suicide of a friend due to a common love interest? Sign me the heck up!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20210418_8.png&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 400px; width: 100%; margin: 0 auto; display: block;&quot; alt=&quot;Wonder Egg Priority Special Edition Broadcast&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center text-gray lh-condensed-ultra f6&quot;&gt;Special Edition Broadcast | Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://anitrendz.net/news/2021/03/30/wonder-egg-priority-special-edition-broadcast-coming-june-29-continues-story/&quot;&gt;Anitredz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;story&quot;&gt;Story&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of how much I respect good psychological anime, I’m going to be as subtle about this as possible: get an egg, save a suicidal person, rinse and repeat, save your own target.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s the innocent-looking synopsis of the anime; sounds straightforward, right? If you’ve never watched a psychological anime before, you’d close the tab and tell me that I should go and rethink my life. However, have you considered this: has anyone who have successfully executed a suicide ever wished to come back? What even driven them to suicide in the first place?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All self-aware species would have some kind of regrets at the end of their mortal life - but those who choose to commit suicide abandon even that, selecting an absolute option to end their suffering (and potentially, some other person’s suffering as well) to solve the problem once and for all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you did successfully save someone who have completed a suicide, would the person thank you from their bottom of their hearts, or hold you in contempt for as long as they continue breathing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wonder Egg Priority centers around four characters who wishes to save a female target from a completed suicide that they were affectionate with; the characters have a diverse set of characteristics that are sometimes directly contradictory, which makes their interactions engaging to watch. Combined with the unique scenario and unusual characters in the form of Acca and Ura-Acca, alongside the anime’s genre pairing with ‘Fantasy’, the entire story is unpredictable and keeps viewers on the edge of their seats as middle-schoolers navigate their way through grasping the concept of suicide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The temptation of death” is something that “smells sweet” - this is a direct reference to how people refer death as “the sweet release of death”. If death is a way for a person to escape all of their problems, then saying that the temptation of death “smells sweet” logically follows - if one were to reach this stage of their life, it then naturally follows that that individual would have a better time being dead than continue living their life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20210418_9.png&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 400px; width: 100%; margin: 0 auto; display: block;&quot; alt=&quot;The two characters being smug&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center text-gray lh-condensed-ultra f6&quot;&gt;Smug Ai &amp;amp; Rika | Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://formeinfullbloom.wordpress.com/2021/01/26/i-hate-you-flower-language-in-wonder-egg-priority-continued/&quot;&gt;Atelier Emily&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some concepts, such as the “Seeno Evil”, who only targets the Wonder Egg girl and “Haters”, who only targets the main characters, are deeply intertwined with symbolism. “Seeno Evil” comes from the phrase “see no evil”; ignoring the causes of suicide is a form of evil on its own. “Haters”, which are derived from “Seeno Evil”, is a form of evil berating the one who protects those who are victims of suicide. Translated to the real world, those who protect the ones who are bullied are treated worse than those who are bullied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;audiovisuals&quot;&gt;Audiovisuals&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently, each flower shown in Wonder Egg priority had some meaning; according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://formeinfullbloom.wordpress.com/2021/01/26/i-hate-you-flower-language-in-wonder-egg-priority-continued/&quot;&gt;Atelier Emily&lt;/a&gt;, orange lilies mean hate, hydrangeas mean thank you, and so on. This should be enough for you to infer that I think highly of the visuals of Wonder Egg priority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The soundtrack used is mostly soft and atmospheric music, as I would expect from an anime of this nature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When combining both the audio and visuals, it gives Wonder Egg priority a complex yet complementary set of stimuli for viewers, which connects the viewers closer to the story than ever possible. While not at the level of Shield Hero or Made In Abyss, the audiovisuals does a decent job at conveying the emotions and scope of the scenes to the viewer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wonder Egg Priority saved the psychological genre for Winter 2021. For a while, there was a drought in anime like that: the very thing that made me fall in love with psychological anime in the first place is how well the medium can portray human moral dilemmas better than any other medium can, &lt;em&gt;because&lt;/em&gt; it is animated, allowing sequences to fall outside the boundaries of human comprehension. Give Wonder Egg Priority a watch :egg:; I’m quite sure you’ll like it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Coding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CodingIndex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James</name></author><summary type="html">As a self-proclaimed professional psychological anime critic, I looked forward to watching Wonder Egg Priority, especially after the flop that was The Promised Neverland Season 2.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1079/110751.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1079/110751.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Dr. Stone: Stone Wars</title><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Dr-Stone-Stone-Wars/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dr. Stone: Stone Wars" /><published>2021-04-18T08:48:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-04-18T08:48:00+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Dr-Stone-Stone-Wars</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Dr-Stone-Stone-Wars/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/anime/Dr-Stone/&quot;&gt;Dr. Stone&lt;/a&gt; is one million percent one of the most mainstream Shounen anime of 2021. This is not without reason - with a unique scenario, good character dynamics, and a mix of science, watching each episode of Dr. Stone is a relaxing leisure activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;science&quot;&gt;Science&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Senkuu, the premier scientist of the stone world, is not only good at science, but good at project management. He takes advantage of his astute understanding of chemistry, history and mathematics to gain an advantage during the series’ main conflict against Tsukasa - creating huge projects that would take even humans of today up to a few months of work to produce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I’ve learned from Senkuu is the existence of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fermi_problem&quot;&gt;Fermi problem&lt;/a&gt;, which Senkuu uses to estimate the number of sold albums by the popular (deceased) singer based on a few fundamental facts during an exploit to trick members in joining his side during the Stone War.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20210418_7.jpeg&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 400px; width: 100%; margin: 0 auto; display: block;&quot; alt=&quot;Senkuu doing an approximation&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center text-gray lh-condensed-ultra f6&quot;&gt;Senkuu thinking | Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hanyallua3/status/1298640758250102785/photo/1&quot;&gt;Twitter @hanyallua3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Stone also illustrates that wartime is the best motivation for technology; due to the upcoming Stone Wars, advancements that would have taken at least another thousand of years to develop only takes a few months - this is shown in the group’s development of radio communication technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;story&quot;&gt;Story&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stone war between what is essentially might and brawns is something that many people have an intrinsic interest in; in history, many generals led wars to victory due to their wit, despite being outnumbered or overpowered in one way or another; meanwhile, military might in terms of weapon systems, manpower and home terrain spelled the end of other wars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the story interest being amplified by elements such as Taiju and Yuzuriha acting as spies, Chrome being captured early in the war, the rapid armament of the Science kingdom, the manpower proliferation of the Tsukasa empire, and the clashing ideologies between Senkuu and Tsukasa, there are many reasons why a viewer would continue to watch “Dr. Stone: Stone Wars”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence, the story is engaging and fun to watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;audiovisuals&quot;&gt;Audiovisuals&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Dr. Stone: Stone Wars” carries its complementary audiovisuals from “Dr. Stone”, even making use of the music in Season 1 as a plot device for garnering support for Senkuu’s army. One thing I didn’t state in the previous review is the use of infographics for any science processes Senkuu uses; as Dr. Stone isn’t a run-of-the-mill anime, the use of a non-standard element might either make or break the view ability of the anime - hence, I am glad that the visuals compliment the unique salient points of the anime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Season 2 is an interesting installment of the “Dr. Stone” series; I’m looking forward to the third season!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Coding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CodingIndex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James</name></author><summary type="html">Dr. Stone is one million percent one of the most mainstream Shounen anime of 2021. This is not without reason - with a unique scenario, good character dynamics, and a mix of science, watching each episode of Dr. Stone is a relaxing leisure activity.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1711/110614.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1711/110614.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Tensei shitara Slime Datta Ken 2nd Season</title><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Tensei-shitara-Slime-Datta-Ken-2nd-Season/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tensei shitara Slime Datta Ken 2nd Season" /><published>2021-04-18T07:33:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-04-18T07:33:00+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Tensei-shitara-Slime-Datta-Ken-2nd-Season</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Tensei-shitara-Slime-Datta-Ken-2nd-Season/">&lt;p&gt;Another great entry to Winter 2021 anime! Tensura was a well-esteemed Isekai anime, which I &lt;a href=&quot;/anime/That-Time-I-Got-Reincarnated-as-a-Slime/&quot;&gt;reviewed&lt;/a&gt;. Despite staying close to the nature of a Isekai anime, it manages to stand out thanks to the humor, good world development and an above average character development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;story&quot;&gt;Story&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this season, we see neighbouring nations starting to take notice of the Jura Tempest Federation. Different nations have different responses, with one nation causing the main conflict of the season due to a corrupt leadership board.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of Tensura, Rimuru forbade the monsters from attacking humans; this rule turned against him, causing him to face his current reality as a monster and sparing no sympathy to the humans who wronged him. This very conflict laid the foundations required for the next potential conflict in Season 3, which would likely be one that affects the world itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20210418_6.jpg&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 400px; width: 100%; margin: 0 auto; display: block;&quot; alt=&quot;Rimuru's Harvest Festival&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center text-gray lh-condensed-ultra f6&quot;&gt;Rimuru's Power Gain | Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=God6fHcPZ1A&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other things that I care about: story consistency &amp;amp; continuity, plot progression and engagement, they were all green to me. Rimuru maintains his humorous approach to situations, although he almost exploded in rage in one instance. The plot moved forward as Rimuru makes deals with the other nations, and there were enough conflicts to keep the viewers on their toes, improving viewer retention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, the story was just as good as it was in Season 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;character-development&quot;&gt;Character Development&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most surprising things to me was the fact that Daikenja (Rimuru’s Great Sage skill) undergone its own Character Development. Despite having no physical form or appearance, Daikenja plays an important role in Tensura - from being the infallible Wikipedia to an auto-battler, to taking care of Rimuru as his consciousness faded into nothingness, it seemed from the onset that Daikenja would be nothing more than a talkative skill that Rimuru could rely upon at any moment. In Season 2, Daikenja experiences &lt;em&gt;growth&lt;/em&gt;; its behaviour evolved, indirectly improving its relations with Rimuru. In the future, it might be possible that Daikenja would play a pivotal role in the plot, potentially being &lt;em&gt;sacrificed&lt;/em&gt; somehow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from Daikenja, Tensura 2 does not have much to speak of in terms of character development; the season was highly focused on building the world and upgrading Rimuru for the next arc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tensura is a very fun series to watch; its light, comedic nature mixed with its Isekai elements alongside the unique elements in its pretext makes the anime a relaxing watch on a cold Saturday night. I look forward to see what Season 3 has in store for me; particularly, I want to see the new characters introduced towards the end of the series interacting with the newly powered-up Rimuru.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Coding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CodingIndex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James</name></author><summary type="html">Another great entry to Winter 2021 anime! Tensura was a well-esteemed Isekai anime, which I reviewed. Despite staying close to the nature of a Isekai anime, it manages to stand out thanks to the humor, good world development and an above average character development.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1271/109841.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1271/109841.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Shingeki no Kyojin: The Final Season</title><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Shingeki-no-Kyojin-The-Final-Season/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Shingeki no Kyojin: The Final Season" /><published>2021-04-18T06:18:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-04-18T06:18:00+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Shingeki-no-Kyojin-The-Final-Season</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Shingeki-no-Kyojin-The-Final-Season/">&lt;p&gt;It might not be an overstatement to say that &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; was the most hyped season of 2021 - “Attack on Titan” finally reaches its climax with this season. The past three seasons, part one and part two alike, have been building up to this very moment, with manga readers guaranteeing that this would be &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; season to look out for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This season reveals how Titans were meant to be used (war) and the true scope of the entire world; there are whole other &lt;em&gt;countries&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;war&lt;/em&gt; between other human nations, concepts foreign to the people who lived within the walls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;story&quot;&gt;Story&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being in a closed box for a few generations causes those within the walls to be out-of-sync with the rest of the world; in fact, no one knew of the existence of human life outside of the walls. On the other hand, being outside the walls in a war-ridden world breeds campaigns of magnitudes only seen during wartime: brainwashing to produce loyal soldiers, enforcement of social class systems to make those of a lower standing more motivated to fight, and of course, spies and the betrayal to the cause.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20210418_4.jpg&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 400px; width: 100%; margin: 0 auto; display: block;&quot; alt=&quot;Braun, Gabi&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center text-gray lh-condensed-ultra f6&quot;&gt;Brain Gabi | Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.denofgeek.com/tv/attack-on-titan-season-4-episode-8-review-assassins-bullet/&quot;&gt;Den of Geek&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also see the death of a certain beloved character as a natural outcome of war. All of these elements elevate “Attack on Titan” from a generic Shounen anime with an interesting pretext to a full-on drama anime with complex characters interacting with a world that is familiar to us, but not them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, as the character complexity grows, so do the relationships. The characters had to make a clear trade-off between supporting their closest friend to protecting the interests of the country. The created tension makes watching the characters interact, or potentially interact, an interesting endeavour, retaining my attention as I delved deeper into the lore of “Attack on Titan”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;audiovisuals&quot;&gt;Audiovisuals&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The audio compliments the visuals very well - when the scene was tense, epic battle music plays, when the scene was dire, calm soothing music plays, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the time skip, most of the characters have to be re-conceptualized - this could prove difficult, as the characters still needed to look &lt;em&gt;similiar&lt;/em&gt; to their younger counterparts while still maintaining the new characteristics and matching that with their new behaviour. I for one, dig Eren’s new look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20210418_5.jpg&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 400px; width: 100%; margin: 0 auto; display: block;&quot; alt=&quot;Eren&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center text-gray lh-condensed-ultra f6&quot;&gt;Eren in Season 4 | Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iovhAs9o0Hw&quot;&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See what I mean? Time-skips are perhaps the hardest things to pull off right for any anime series both story-wise and appearance-wise, but I think “Attack on Titan” did a good job in both aspects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;character-development&quot;&gt;Character Development&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A common time-skip troupe for anime would show a slightly matured main character with new powerful techniques and mental resilience useful either for the next arc, or towards the conclusion of a story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In “Attack on Titan”, this troupe is carried forward, &lt;em&gt;but&lt;/em&gt; because this wasn’t a “training arc time-skip”, you could &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; that the relationships between all the characters change; a particular example would be how the rest of the crew viewed Eren - once a headfast teenager who thoughtlessly jumped straight into situations and swore to kill all Titans, he became a manipulative adult who carefully plans his approach, albeit still planning to kill all Titans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Characters such as Hange-san grows into her military appointment, displaying her confidence in decision making despite still being unsure when outside the public eye. There are also characters that don’t experience growth due to plot reasons, such as Reiner, who seems to suffer some variant of Post Traumatic Stress Disorder, and Levi, who is still a badass that can cut Titans down in the most epic manner possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A balance of characters who experience growth, and characters that don’t experience growth links the seasons together and ensures that they are at least somewhat continuous; so that viewers don’t feel like they’re watching something completely different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am happy to report that “Attack on Titan” Season 4 lives up to its hype; there isn’t much to fault it for, and I definitely enjoyed watching it from start to finish. Give it a watch :cinema:!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Coding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CodingIndex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James</name></author><summary type="html">It might not be an overstatement to say that this was the most hyped season of 2021 - “Attack on Titan” finally reaches its climax with this season. The past three seasons, part one and part two alike, have been building up to this very moment, with manga readers guaranteeing that this would be the season to look out for.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1000/110531.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1000/110531.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Yakusoku no Neverland 2nd Season</title><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/The-Promised-Neverland-Season-2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Yakusoku no Neverland 2nd Season" /><published>2021-04-18T03:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-04-18T03:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/anime/The-Promised-Neverland-Season-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/The-Promised-Neverland-Season-2/">&lt;p&gt;Argh, what a way to start my Winter 2021 binge watching session! &lt;a href=&quot;/anime/The-Promised-Neverland/&quot;&gt;The Promised Neverland Season 1&lt;/a&gt; was one of my favourite anime of all time - so, I was looking forward to seeing what Season 2 had in store for us, especially after seeing the successful grand escape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20210418_3.gif&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 400px; width: 100%; margin: 0 auto; display: block;&quot; alt=&quot;Grand Escape&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center text-gray lh-condensed-ultra f6&quot;&gt;Promised Neverland Kids seeing sunlight | Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://couldnt-think-of-a-better-name.tumblr.com/post/184229591826/i-am-back&quot;&gt;Tumblr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Season 2 was a disaster. From the escaping kids having nothing short of pure plot armor, to the sudden appearance and world dynamics introduced by the demons, to how rushed the whole season seemed to be, I’m quite sure many would agree that this dumpster fire of a season brings shame to the franchise’s name. As a anime-only consumer of The Promised Neverland, I have no knowledge of the events that transpired within the manga, although I am aware that the anime skips many important world-building elements that made Season 1 a masterpiece.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;story-anime-only&quot;&gt;Story (Anime-only)&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To respect the original material, I will only talk about how the story was portrayed in the anime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Season 1, demons were these mysterious beings that ate humans - in fact, I can’t remember any scenes that outright illustrated a demon. To me, the mystery contributes to the engagement of the story, and enhances the meaning behind the actions taken by the escapees: humans are, after all, generally afraid of both death and the unknown, which causes the audience to be curious about how the characters approach this fear, retaining engagement. However, in Season 2, the first scene opens with a demon chasing the children, which &lt;em&gt;they somehow escape&lt;/em&gt;, outright removing the mystery element from the story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From that point on, the series needed an important distinguishing factor that would serve as the overarching goal for the main characters. In Season 1, this was to escape from the human farms; in Season 2, this was to reach the human world promised by William Minerva. The main essence of the series was completely changed the moment this distinguishing factor changed - I felt like I was watching a completely different anime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, there were many dilemmas faced by Emma that was solved way too quickly without proper exploration; for instance, to take the live of another living being for the sake of survival, or to be on friendly terms with demons that have terrorized humans for thousands of years, or to convince Norman (a super-highly-very intelligent kid) that his master-plan is a mistake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is more, the sorry excuse of a power-point slideshow at the end of Season 2 made the story highly discontinuous - remember, Season 2’s overarching goal is to reach the human world. The season bit off more than it could chew by compressing Emma’s exploits to unite both worlds into a less than 10 minute power-point presentation, and then trying to bury its misdoings to the series by showing an “emotional” reunion between Emma and Phil, which was honestly not very touching given that we literally saw them part in the same episode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;audiovisuals&quot;&gt;Audiovisuals&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Putting aside the story, The Promised Neverland has great audiovisuals. Here, have a listen to one of the soundtracks that played in the anime:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe style=&quot;margin: 0 auto; display: block&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/at6EjgWFeEk&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center text-gray lh-condensed-ultra f6&quot;&gt;Evil-blooded Girl OST | Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=at6EjgWFeEk&quot;&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The visuals are as good as that in Season 1, which is a nice thing to see given how the substance was a dumpster fire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;characters&quot;&gt;Characters&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Same as Season 1, but everyone gains plot armor, Norman gains some form of political power, and Ray becomes a useful tool instead of possessing independent thinking. In a nutshell, the characters aren’t consistent to what was observed in Season 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This could have been made better by introducing conflict between Emma and Ray; after all, they are both supposed to be of equal standing in Season 2. However, Season 2 turned out more to be Emma’s season than a “Promised Neverland” season. Very bland, very predictable, very disappointing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bad season. I hoped to see a great continuation to a series I loved so much, but alas, good times don’t last. You would be better off watching the other :star: anime of Winter 2021.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Coding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CodingIndex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James</name></author><summary type="html">Argh, what a way to start my Winter 2021 binge watching session! The Promised Neverland Season 1 was one of my favourite anime of all time - so, I was looking forward to seeing what Season 2 had in store for us, especially after seeing the successful grand escape.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1815/110626.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1815/110626.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Boku wa Tomodachi ga Sukunai</title><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Boku-wa-Tomodachi-ga-Sukanai/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Boku wa Tomodachi ga Sukunai" /><published>2021-04-18T01:44:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-04-18T01:44:00+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Boku-wa-Tomodachi-ga-Sukanai</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Boku-wa-Tomodachi-ga-Sukanai/">&lt;p&gt;After enjoying &lt;a href=&quot;/anime/Yahari-Ore-no-Seishun-Love-Comedy-wa-Machigatteiru/&quot;&gt;Oregairu&lt;/a&gt;, I still had some time before all the Winter 2021 anime finished airing, so I decided to pick up “Boku wa Tomodachi ga Sukanai” as an apt alternative; this review covers both Season 1 and Season 2 (NEXT).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&quot;/anime/Yahari-Ore-no-Seishun-Love-Comedy-wa-Machigatteiru/&quot;&gt;Oregairu&lt;/a&gt; review, I have mentioned that I disliked romance anime, because I could not understand them well, especially how the plot influences the relationship between the characters. It seems that for most romance anime (the ones that I have watched), it can all be boiled down to: “I spend enough time with this person, hence I like this person”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20210418_2.jpg&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 400px; width: 100%; margin: 0 auto; display: block;&quot; alt=&quot;Crew&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center text-gray lh-condensed-ultra f6&quot;&gt;The crew of I don't have many friends | Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://jakecoker.wordpress.com/2017/11/21/first-impressions-boku-wa-tomodachi-ga-sukunai-i-dont-have-many-friends/&quot;&gt;JakeCoker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Boku wa Tomodachi ga Sukunai”, or “I don’t have many friends” is a phrase that resonates with me; however, the contents of the anime contradicts this phrase in the very first episode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;story&quot;&gt;Story&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Super fast plot setting: A lonely guy and girl met, creating a “Neighbours Club” for the politically unbeatable reason of being good neighbours to others in the name of god. The true purpose of the club? To make friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re sharp, you’d have already noticed a discrepancy in the plot setting; how can socially reclusive characters &lt;em&gt;start&lt;/em&gt; a club for the sake of being friends with one another? To start a club, there are many processes for you to go through, such as social interaction with the teacher-in-charge, recruiting enough members, and potentially discussing the terms with the Student Council to obtain a budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The male protagonist, Hasegawa Kodaka, is supposedly a scary-looking dude, while the club initiator, Mikazuki Yozora, is a highly logical and anti-social character. If you’d just met another person with no friends, &lt;em&gt;would you start a club with that person on the first day&lt;/em&gt;? There are some mismatches between the personality and behaviour of the characters, which makes the series fairly inconsistent and incomprehensible to watch at times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The climax of the series in Season 2 (NEXT), while logically sound, is highly improbable. A quick non-spoiler context-setting: for certain reasons, the male protagonist starts avoiding everyone else. The entire crew then proceeds to &lt;em&gt;never approach the guy&lt;/em&gt; to seek clarification or fix their relationship; instead, this story-based conflict ends from an absurd event that can be described as “important information in audio, useless visuals at the back”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The series establishes its own manner of troupes; a classic routine in each scene would be: Kashiwazaki Sena does something, Mikazuki Yozora rebukes this, Hasegawa Kodaka sighs. Another classic routine would be as follows: Shiguma Rika does something, Hasegawa Kodaka pretends to be oblivious, Shiguma Rika rebukes with disappointment. Established routines are dangerous for an anime in the genre of “Slice-of-Life”; being predictable is one way to lose audience attention and general interest to the series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite its flaws, I was able to follow along the story to the very bitter end; there were some enjoyable and memorable parts that were &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; relevant to the “romance” part of the series, such as the pool incident with Sena and the various flashback scenes by Kodaka. For a romance anime, however, the almost non-existent slope in relationship building thanks to Kodaka’s faults leaves much to be desired. By the end of NEXT, he makes up his mind to do something about it, but there has not been a Season 3 since 2013.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would not recommend watching “I don’t have many friends” unless you run out of anime in your bucket list (i.e. improbable). Instead, you should watch Oregairu, Bunny Girl Senpai and Shigatsu wa Kimi no Uso; if you haven’t already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Coding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CodingIndex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James</name></author><summary type="html">After enjoying Oregairu, I still had some time before all the Winter 2021 anime finished airing, so I decided to pick up “Boku wa Tomodachi ga Sukanai” as an apt alternative; this review covers both Season 1 and Season 2 (NEXT).</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/3/44724.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/3/44724.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>