<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/feed/anime.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-04-25T06:31:32+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/feed/anime.xml</id><title type="html">CodingIndex’s Random Shenanigans | Anime</title><subtitle>A (human) index that likes to code. Also drinks way too much coffee.</subtitle><author><name>James</name></author><entry><title type="html">Jaku-Chara Tomozaki-kun</title><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Jaku-Chara-Tomozaki-kun/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jaku-Chara Tomozaki-kun" /><published>2021-04-18T10:07:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-04-18T10:07:00+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Jaku-Chara-Tomozaki-kun</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Jaku-Chara-Tomozaki-kun/">&lt;p&gt;Right, another romance anime. I promise that I still love Psychological anime, but recently, I’ve started to consume romance high-school anime like crazy, thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;/anime/Yahari-Ore-no-Seishun-Love-Comedy-wa-Machigatteiru/&quot;&gt;Oregairu&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/anime/Horimiya/&quot;&gt;Horimiya&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;story&quot;&gt;Story&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the concept of gaming as a base, Jaku-Chara Tomozaki-kun follows Tomozaki-kun, a god at a brawl game, as he plays through the game of life as the lowest-possible-tier character. The game of life requires social interaction, which many people, including myself, is completely inept at wielding competently; for Tomozaki-kun, who has no friends, and no life outside of gaming, social interaction is a skill he kept at level 0 since he was born.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After an offline meeting with NO-NAME, they discover that they come from the same school, and the god player of the brawl game is a loser in real life. Determined to change this, both Tomozaki and Aoi decided to try and raise Tomozaki’s level, at least to the level where he can get a girlfriend by the end of summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An interesting concept aside, I personally believe that chemistry is important when trying to pair ideas together. Gaming + romance is something that has been explored to death in other forms, such as the case in &lt;a href=&quot;https://myanimelist.net/anime/8525/Kami_nomi_zo_Shiru_Sekai&quot;&gt;The World God Only Knows&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://myanimelist.net/anime/21877/High_Score_Girl&quot;&gt;High Score Girl&lt;/a&gt;. Hence, I couldn’t help but feel like the combination has become closer to being cliché than novel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The anime is systematic in ensuring its viewers understand the story flow within the first two episodes; Aoi writes goals that Tomozaki should try and achieve before any conflict could even arise in the story, and comes back to this board regularly to check on Tomozaki’s progress. This creates a clear path for the storyline that is difficult to deviate from, which makes some conversations within the story quite awkward and forced, albeit that might be the writer’s goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later on in the story, Tomozaki breaks out of these systematic goals and decides to just be himself for a while, restoring a factor of unpredictability that all anime should have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20210418_10.jpg&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 400px; width: 100%; margin: 0 auto; display: block;&quot; alt=&quot;Characters in Jaku-Chara Tomozaki-kun&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center text-gray lh-condensed-ultra f6&quot;&gt;Characters in Jaku-Chara Tomozaki-kun | Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/myanimelist/status/1324577646349529088&quot;&gt;Tiwitter @myanimelist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jaku-Chara Tomozaki-kun is, at the moment, an incomplete story; by observing how the plot is progressing, there is probably a whole deal more that the story authors are planning, such that “multiple routes” become available eventually. Abducting backwards, this means that the plot progression is slow, which is a norm for high school romance anime where the main protagonist is a social recluse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, viewing the beginnings of a romance anime is still relatively enjoyable, despite some portions of the anime being difficult to watch due to how stale or awkward they were - I hope this is all just part of the setup towards something greater in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;character-development&quot;&gt;Character Development&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The series is at the beginning, so there is not much character development among all the characters. The two exceptions to this rule would be Tomozaki himself, and Nanami - both of which grew significantly within this first season. Tomozaki is an obvious case, considering the entire anime surrounds him stepping out of his comfort zone to try out the game of life, while Nanami, on the other hand, gets over her inferiority complex as she tries to fight against her rival.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Character development is an important aspect in an anime with little to no world-building, and a almost-stagnant plot progression, as it is the only factor that engages the viewers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;audiovisuals&quot;&gt;Audiovisuals&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not going to lie, the main character looks a lot like me: ugly and a sore sight no matter where he goes. Otherwise, the visuals are pretty, and the audio doesn’t get in the way; I’d say that’s good enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the moment, Jaku-Chara Tomozaki-kun is a mediocre anime. Perhaps it’ll get better as new seasons are released, but it shouldn’t be at the top of your to-watch list, unless that list is empty. I’ll look out for what the next season (if any) brings!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Coding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CodingIndex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James</name></author><summary type="html">Right, another romance anime. I promise that I still love Psychological anime, but recently, I’ve started to consume romance high-school anime like crazy, thanks to Oregairu and Horimiya.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1120/109232.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1120/109232.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Wonder Egg Priority</title><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Wonder-Egg-Priority/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wonder Egg Priority" /><published>2021-04-18T09:39:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-04-18T09:39:00+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Wonder-Egg-Priority</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Wonder-Egg-Priority/">&lt;p&gt;As a self-proclaimed professional psychological anime critic, I looked forward to watching Wonder Egg Priority, especially after the flop that was &lt;a href=&quot;/anime/The-Promised-Neverland-Season-2/&quot;&gt;The Promised Neverland Season 2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And you know what, Wonder Egg Priority was wonderful. An anime that explores the suicide of a friend due to a common love interest? Sign me the heck up!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20210418_8.png&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 400px; width: 100%; margin: 0 auto; display: block;&quot; alt=&quot;Wonder Egg Priority Special Edition Broadcast&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center text-gray lh-condensed-ultra f6&quot;&gt;Special Edition Broadcast | Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://anitrendz.net/news/2021/03/30/wonder-egg-priority-special-edition-broadcast-coming-june-29-continues-story/&quot;&gt;Anitredz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;story&quot;&gt;Story&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of how much I respect good psychological anime, I’m going to be as subtle about this as possible: get an egg, save a suicidal person, rinse and repeat, save your own target.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s the innocent-looking synopsis of the anime; sounds straightforward, right? If you’ve never watched a psychological anime before, you’d close the tab and tell me that I should go and rethink my life. However, have you considered this: has anyone who have successfully executed a suicide ever wished to come back? What even driven them to suicide in the first place?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All self-aware species would have some kind of regrets at the end of their mortal life - but those who choose to commit suicide abandon even that, selecting an absolute option to end their suffering (and potentially, some other person’s suffering as well) to solve the problem once and for all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you did successfully save someone who have completed a suicide, would the person thank you from their bottom of their hearts, or hold you in contempt for as long as they continue breathing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wonder Egg Priority centers around four characters who wishes to save a female target from a completed suicide that they were affectionate with; the characters have a diverse set of characteristics that are sometimes directly contradictory, which makes their interactions engaging to watch. Combined with the unique scenario and unusual characters in the form of Acca and Ura-Acca, alongside the anime’s genre pairing with ‘Fantasy’, the entire story is unpredictable and keeps viewers on the edge of their seats as middle-schoolers navigate their way through grasping the concept of suicide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The temptation of death” is something that “smells sweet” - this is a direct reference to how people refer death as “the sweet release of death”. If death is a way for a person to escape all of their problems, then saying that the temptation of death “smells sweet” logically follows - if one were to reach this stage of their life, it then naturally follows that that individual would have a better time being dead than continue living their life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20210418_9.png&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 400px; width: 100%; margin: 0 auto; display: block;&quot; alt=&quot;The two characters being smug&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center text-gray lh-condensed-ultra f6&quot;&gt;Smug Ai &amp;amp; Rika | Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://formeinfullbloom.wordpress.com/2021/01/26/i-hate-you-flower-language-in-wonder-egg-priority-continued/&quot;&gt;Atelier Emily&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some concepts, such as the “Seeno Evil”, who only targets the Wonder Egg girl and “Haters”, who only targets the main characters, are deeply intertwined with symbolism. “Seeno Evil” comes from the phrase “see no evil”; ignoring the causes of suicide is a form of evil on its own. “Haters”, which are derived from “Seeno Evil”, is a form of evil berating the one who protects those who are victims of suicide. Translated to the real world, those who protect the ones who are bullied are treated worse than those who are bullied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;audiovisuals&quot;&gt;Audiovisuals&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently, each flower shown in Wonder Egg priority had some meaning; according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://formeinfullbloom.wordpress.com/2021/01/26/i-hate-you-flower-language-in-wonder-egg-priority-continued/&quot;&gt;Atelier Emily&lt;/a&gt;, orange lilies mean hate, hydrangeas mean thank you, and so on. This should be enough for you to infer that I think highly of the visuals of Wonder Egg priority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The soundtrack used is mostly soft and atmospheric music, as I would expect from an anime of this nature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When combining both the audio and visuals, it gives Wonder Egg priority a complex yet complementary set of stimuli for viewers, which connects the viewers closer to the story than ever possible. While not at the level of Shield Hero or Made In Abyss, the audiovisuals does a decent job at conveying the emotions and scope of the scenes to the viewer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wonder Egg Priority saved the psychological genre for Winter 2021. For a while, there was a drought in anime like that: the very thing that made me fall in love with psychological anime in the first place is how well the medium can portray human moral dilemmas better than any other medium can, &lt;em&gt;because&lt;/em&gt; it is animated, allowing sequences to fall outside the boundaries of human comprehension. Give Wonder Egg Priority a watch :egg:; I’m quite sure you’ll like it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Coding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CodingIndex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James</name></author><summary type="html">As a self-proclaimed professional psychological anime critic, I looked forward to watching Wonder Egg Priority, especially after the flop that was The Promised Neverland Season 2.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1079/110751.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1079/110751.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Dr. Stone: Stone Wars</title><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Dr-Stone-Stone-Wars/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dr. Stone: Stone Wars" /><published>2021-04-18T08:48:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-04-18T08:48:00+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Dr-Stone-Stone-Wars</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Dr-Stone-Stone-Wars/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/anime/Dr-Stone/&quot;&gt;Dr. Stone&lt;/a&gt; is one million percent one of the most mainstream Shounen anime of 2021. This is not without reason - with a unique scenario, good character dynamics, and a mix of science, watching each episode of Dr. Stone is a relaxing leisure activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;science&quot;&gt;Science&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Senkuu, the premier scientist of the stone world, is not only good at science, but good at project management. He takes advantage of his astute understanding of chemistry, history and mathematics to gain an advantage during the series’ main conflict against Tsukasa - creating huge projects that would take even humans of today up to a few months of work to produce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I’ve learned from Senkuu is the existence of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fermi_problem&quot;&gt;Fermi problem&lt;/a&gt;, which Senkuu uses to estimate the number of sold albums by the popular (deceased) singer based on a few fundamental facts during an exploit to trick members in joining his side during the Stone War.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20210418_7.jpeg&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 400px; width: 100%; margin: 0 auto; display: block;&quot; alt=&quot;Senkuu doing an approximation&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center text-gray lh-condensed-ultra f6&quot;&gt;Senkuu thinking | Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hanyallua3/status/1298640758250102785/photo/1&quot;&gt;Twitter @hanyallua3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Stone also illustrates that wartime is the best motivation for technology; due to the upcoming Stone Wars, advancements that would have taken at least another thousand of years to develop only takes a few months - this is shown in the group’s development of radio communication technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;story&quot;&gt;Story&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stone war between what is essentially might and brawns is something that many people have an intrinsic interest in; in history, many generals led wars to victory due to their wit, despite being outnumbered or overpowered in one way or another; meanwhile, military might in terms of weapon systems, manpower and home terrain spelled the end of other wars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the story interest being amplified by elements such as Taiju and Yuzuriha acting as spies, Chrome being captured early in the war, the rapid armament of the Science kingdom, the manpower proliferation of the Tsukasa empire, and the clashing ideologies between Senkuu and Tsukasa, there are many reasons why a viewer would continue to watch “Dr. Stone: Stone Wars”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence, the story is engaging and fun to watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;audiovisuals&quot;&gt;Audiovisuals&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Dr. Stone: Stone Wars” carries its complementary audiovisuals from “Dr. Stone”, even making use of the music in Season 1 as a plot device for garnering support for Senkuu’s army. One thing I didn’t state in the previous review is the use of infographics for any science processes Senkuu uses; as Dr. Stone isn’t a run-of-the-mill anime, the use of a non-standard element might either make or break the view ability of the anime - hence, I am glad that the visuals compliment the unique salient points of the anime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Season 2 is an interesting installment of the “Dr. Stone” series; I’m looking forward to the third season!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Coding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CodingIndex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James</name></author><summary type="html">Dr. Stone is one million percent one of the most mainstream Shounen anime of 2021. This is not without reason - with a unique scenario, good character dynamics, and a mix of science, watching each episode of Dr. Stone is a relaxing leisure activity.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1711/110614.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1711/110614.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Tensei shitara Slime Datta Ken 2nd Season</title><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Tensei-shitara-Slime-Datta-Ken-2nd-Season/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tensei shitara Slime Datta Ken 2nd Season" /><published>2021-04-18T07:33:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-04-18T07:33:00+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Tensei-shitara-Slime-Datta-Ken-2nd-Season</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Tensei-shitara-Slime-Datta-Ken-2nd-Season/">&lt;p&gt;Another great entry to Winter 2021 anime! Tensura was a well-esteemed Isekai anime, which I &lt;a href=&quot;/anime/That-Time-I-Got-Reincarnated-as-a-Slime/&quot;&gt;reviewed&lt;/a&gt;. Despite staying close to the nature of a Isekai anime, it manages to stand out thanks to the humor, good world development and an above average character development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;story&quot;&gt;Story&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this season, we see neighbouring nations starting to take notice of the Jura Tempest Federation. Different nations have different responses, with one nation causing the main conflict of the season due to a corrupt leadership board.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of Tensura, Rimuru forbade the monsters from attacking humans; this rule turned against him, causing him to face his current reality as a monster and sparing no sympathy to the humans who wronged him. This very conflict laid the foundations required for the next potential conflict in Season 3, which would likely be one that affects the world itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20210418_6.jpg&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 400px; width: 100%; margin: 0 auto; display: block;&quot; alt=&quot;Rimuru's Harvest Festival&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center text-gray lh-condensed-ultra f6&quot;&gt;Rimuru's Power Gain | Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=God6fHcPZ1A&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other things that I care about: story consistency &amp;amp; continuity, plot progression and engagement, they were all green to me. Rimuru maintains his humorous approach to situations, although he almost exploded in rage in one instance. The plot moved forward as Rimuru makes deals with the other nations, and there were enough conflicts to keep the viewers on their toes, improving viewer retention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, the story was just as good as it was in Season 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;character-development&quot;&gt;Character Development&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most surprising things to me was the fact that Daikenja (Rimuru’s Great Sage skill) undergone its own Character Development. Despite having no physical form or appearance, Daikenja plays an important role in Tensura - from being the infallible Wikipedia to an auto-battler, to taking care of Rimuru as his consciousness faded into nothingness, it seemed from the onset that Daikenja would be nothing more than a talkative skill that Rimuru could rely upon at any moment. In Season 2, Daikenja experiences &lt;em&gt;growth&lt;/em&gt;; its behaviour evolved, indirectly improving its relations with Rimuru. In the future, it might be possible that Daikenja would play a pivotal role in the plot, potentially being &lt;em&gt;sacrificed&lt;/em&gt; somehow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from Daikenja, Tensura 2 does not have much to speak of in terms of character development; the season was highly focused on building the world and upgrading Rimuru for the next arc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tensura is a very fun series to watch; its light, comedic nature mixed with its Isekai elements alongside the unique elements in its pretext makes the anime a relaxing watch on a cold Saturday night. I look forward to see what Season 3 has in store for me; particularly, I want to see the new characters introduced towards the end of the series interacting with the newly powered-up Rimuru.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Coding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CodingIndex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James</name></author><summary type="html">Another great entry to Winter 2021 anime! Tensura was a well-esteemed Isekai anime, which I reviewed. Despite staying close to the nature of a Isekai anime, it manages to stand out thanks to the humor, good world development and an above average character development.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1271/109841.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1271/109841.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Shingeki no Kyojin: The Final Season</title><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Shingeki-no-Kyojin-The-Final-Season/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Shingeki no Kyojin: The Final Season" /><published>2021-04-18T06:18:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-04-18T06:18:00+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Shingeki-no-Kyojin-The-Final-Season</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Shingeki-no-Kyojin-The-Final-Season/">&lt;p&gt;It might not be an overstatement to say that &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; was the most hyped season of 2021 - “Attack on Titan” finally reaches its climax with this season. The past three seasons, part one and part two alike, have been building up to this very moment, with manga readers guaranteeing that this would be &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; season to look out for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This season reveals how Titans were meant to be used (war) and the true scope of the entire world; there are whole other &lt;em&gt;countries&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;war&lt;/em&gt; between other human nations, concepts foreign to the people who lived within the walls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;story&quot;&gt;Story&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being in a closed box for a few generations causes those within the walls to be out-of-sync with the rest of the world; in fact, no one knew of the existence of human life outside of the walls. On the other hand, being outside the walls in a war-ridden world breeds campaigns of magnitudes only seen during wartime: brainwashing to produce loyal soldiers, enforcement of social class systems to make those of a lower standing more motivated to fight, and of course, spies and the betrayal to the cause.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20210418_4.jpg&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 400px; width: 100%; margin: 0 auto; display: block;&quot; alt=&quot;Braun, Gabi&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center text-gray lh-condensed-ultra f6&quot;&gt;Brain Gabi | Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.denofgeek.com/tv/attack-on-titan-season-4-episode-8-review-assassins-bullet/&quot;&gt;Den of Geek&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also see the death of a certain beloved character as a natural outcome of war. All of these elements elevate “Attack on Titan” from a generic Shounen anime with an interesting pretext to a full-on drama anime with complex characters interacting with a world that is familiar to us, but not them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, as the character complexity grows, so do the relationships. The characters had to make a clear trade-off between supporting their closest friend to protecting the interests of the country. The created tension makes watching the characters interact, or potentially interact, an interesting endeavour, retaining my attention as I delved deeper into the lore of “Attack on Titan”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;audiovisuals&quot;&gt;Audiovisuals&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The audio compliments the visuals very well - when the scene was tense, epic battle music plays, when the scene was dire, calm soothing music plays, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the time skip, most of the characters have to be re-conceptualized - this could prove difficult, as the characters still needed to look &lt;em&gt;similiar&lt;/em&gt; to their younger counterparts while still maintaining the new characteristics and matching that with their new behaviour. I for one, dig Eren’s new look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20210418_5.jpg&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 400px; width: 100%; margin: 0 auto; display: block;&quot; alt=&quot;Eren&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center text-gray lh-condensed-ultra f6&quot;&gt;Eren in Season 4 | Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iovhAs9o0Hw&quot;&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See what I mean? Time-skips are perhaps the hardest things to pull off right for any anime series both story-wise and appearance-wise, but I think “Attack on Titan” did a good job in both aspects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;character-development&quot;&gt;Character Development&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A common time-skip troupe for anime would show a slightly matured main character with new powerful techniques and mental resilience useful either for the next arc, or towards the conclusion of a story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In “Attack on Titan”, this troupe is carried forward, &lt;em&gt;but&lt;/em&gt; because this wasn’t a “training arc time-skip”, you could &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; that the relationships between all the characters change; a particular example would be how the rest of the crew viewed Eren - once a headfast teenager who thoughtlessly jumped straight into situations and swore to kill all Titans, he became a manipulative adult who carefully plans his approach, albeit still planning to kill all Titans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Characters such as Hange-san grows into her military appointment, displaying her confidence in decision making despite still being unsure when outside the public eye. There are also characters that don’t experience growth due to plot reasons, such as Reiner, who seems to suffer some variant of Post Traumatic Stress Disorder, and Levi, who is still a badass that can cut Titans down in the most epic manner possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A balance of characters who experience growth, and characters that don’t experience growth links the seasons together and ensures that they are at least somewhat continuous; so that viewers don’t feel like they’re watching something completely different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am happy to report that “Attack on Titan” Season 4 lives up to its hype; there isn’t much to fault it for, and I definitely enjoyed watching it from start to finish. Give it a watch :cinema:!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Coding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CodingIndex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James</name></author><summary type="html">It might not be an overstatement to say that this was the most hyped season of 2021 - “Attack on Titan” finally reaches its climax with this season. The past three seasons, part one and part two alike, have been building up to this very moment, with manga readers guaranteeing that this would be the season to look out for.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1000/110531.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1000/110531.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Yakusoku no Neverland 2nd Season</title><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/The-Promised-Neverland-Season-2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Yakusoku no Neverland 2nd Season" /><published>2021-04-18T03:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-04-18T03:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/anime/The-Promised-Neverland-Season-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/The-Promised-Neverland-Season-2/">&lt;p&gt;Argh, what a way to start my Winter 2021 binge watching session! &lt;a href=&quot;/anime/The-Promised-Neverland/&quot;&gt;The Promised Neverland Season 1&lt;/a&gt; was one of my favourite anime of all time - so, I was looking forward to seeing what Season 2 had in store for us, especially after seeing the successful grand escape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20210418_3.gif&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 400px; width: 100%; margin: 0 auto; display: block;&quot; alt=&quot;Grand Escape&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center text-gray lh-condensed-ultra f6&quot;&gt;Promised Neverland Kids seeing sunlight | Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://couldnt-think-of-a-better-name.tumblr.com/post/184229591826/i-am-back&quot;&gt;Tumblr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Season 2 was a disaster. From the escaping kids having nothing short of pure plot armor, to the sudden appearance and world dynamics introduced by the demons, to how rushed the whole season seemed to be, I’m quite sure many would agree that this dumpster fire of a season brings shame to the franchise’s name. As a anime-only consumer of The Promised Neverland, I have no knowledge of the events that transpired within the manga, although I am aware that the anime skips many important world-building elements that made Season 1 a masterpiece.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;story-anime-only&quot;&gt;Story (Anime-only)&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To respect the original material, I will only talk about how the story was portrayed in the anime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Season 1, demons were these mysterious beings that ate humans - in fact, I can’t remember any scenes that outright illustrated a demon. To me, the mystery contributes to the engagement of the story, and enhances the meaning behind the actions taken by the escapees: humans are, after all, generally afraid of both death and the unknown, which causes the audience to be curious about how the characters approach this fear, retaining engagement. However, in Season 2, the first scene opens with a demon chasing the children, which &lt;em&gt;they somehow escape&lt;/em&gt;, outright removing the mystery element from the story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From that point on, the series needed an important distinguishing factor that would serve as the overarching goal for the main characters. In Season 1, this was to escape from the human farms; in Season 2, this was to reach the human world promised by William Minerva. The main essence of the series was completely changed the moment this distinguishing factor changed - I felt like I was watching a completely different anime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, there were many dilemmas faced by Emma that was solved way too quickly without proper exploration; for instance, to take the live of another living being for the sake of survival, or to be on friendly terms with demons that have terrorized humans for thousands of years, or to convince Norman (a super-highly-very intelligent kid) that his master-plan is a mistake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is more, the sorry excuse of a power-point slideshow at the end of Season 2 made the story highly discontinuous - remember, Season 2’s overarching goal is to reach the human world. The season bit off more than it could chew by compressing Emma’s exploits to unite both worlds into a less than 10 minute power-point presentation, and then trying to bury its misdoings to the series by showing an “emotional” reunion between Emma and Phil, which was honestly not very touching given that we literally saw them part in the same episode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;audiovisuals&quot;&gt;Audiovisuals&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Putting aside the story, The Promised Neverland has great audiovisuals. Here, have a listen to one of the soundtracks that played in the anime:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe style=&quot;margin: 0 auto; display: block&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/at6EjgWFeEk&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center text-gray lh-condensed-ultra f6&quot;&gt;Evil-blooded Girl OST | Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=at6EjgWFeEk&quot;&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The visuals are as good as that in Season 1, which is a nice thing to see given how the substance was a dumpster fire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;characters&quot;&gt;Characters&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Same as Season 1, but everyone gains plot armor, Norman gains some form of political power, and Ray becomes a useful tool instead of possessing independent thinking. In a nutshell, the characters aren’t consistent to what was observed in Season 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This could have been made better by introducing conflict between Emma and Ray; after all, they are both supposed to be of equal standing in Season 2. However, Season 2 turned out more to be Emma’s season than a “Promised Neverland” season. Very bland, very predictable, very disappointing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bad season. I hoped to see a great continuation to a series I loved so much, but alas, good times don’t last. You would be better off watching the other :star: anime of Winter 2021.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Coding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CodingIndex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James</name></author><summary type="html">Argh, what a way to start my Winter 2021 binge watching session! The Promised Neverland Season 1 was one of my favourite anime of all time - so, I was looking forward to seeing what Season 2 had in store for us, especially after seeing the successful grand escape.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1815/110626.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1815/110626.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Boku wa Tomodachi ga Sukunai</title><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Boku-wa-Tomodachi-ga-Sukanai/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Boku wa Tomodachi ga Sukunai" /><published>2021-04-18T01:44:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-04-18T01:44:00+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Boku-wa-Tomodachi-ga-Sukanai</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Boku-wa-Tomodachi-ga-Sukanai/">&lt;p&gt;After enjoying &lt;a href=&quot;/anime/Yahari-Ore-no-Seishun-Love-Comedy-wa-Machigatteiru/&quot;&gt;Oregairu&lt;/a&gt;, I still had some time before all the Winter 2021 anime finished airing, so I decided to pick up “Boku wa Tomodachi ga Sukanai” as an apt alternative; this review covers both Season 1 and Season 2 (NEXT).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&quot;/anime/Yahari-Ore-no-Seishun-Love-Comedy-wa-Machigatteiru/&quot;&gt;Oregairu&lt;/a&gt; review, I have mentioned that I disliked romance anime, because I could not understand them well, especially how the plot influences the relationship between the characters. It seems that for most romance anime (the ones that I have watched), it can all be boiled down to: “I spend enough time with this person, hence I like this person”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20210418_2.jpg&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 400px; width: 100%; margin: 0 auto; display: block;&quot; alt=&quot;Crew&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center text-gray lh-condensed-ultra f6&quot;&gt;The crew of I don't have many friends | Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://jakecoker.wordpress.com/2017/11/21/first-impressions-boku-wa-tomodachi-ga-sukunai-i-dont-have-many-friends/&quot;&gt;JakeCoker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Boku wa Tomodachi ga Sukunai”, or “I don’t have many friends” is a phrase that resonates with me; however, the contents of the anime contradicts this phrase in the very first episode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;story&quot;&gt;Story&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Super fast plot setting: A lonely guy and girl met, creating a “Neighbours Club” for the politically unbeatable reason of being good neighbours to others in the name of god. The true purpose of the club? To make friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re sharp, you’d have already noticed a discrepancy in the plot setting; how can socially reclusive characters &lt;em&gt;start&lt;/em&gt; a club for the sake of being friends with one another? To start a club, there are many processes for you to go through, such as social interaction with the teacher-in-charge, recruiting enough members, and potentially discussing the terms with the Student Council to obtain a budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The male protagonist, Hasegawa Kodaka, is supposedly a scary-looking dude, while the club initiator, Mikazuki Yozora, is a highly logical and anti-social character. If you’d just met another person with no friends, &lt;em&gt;would you start a club with that person on the first day&lt;/em&gt;? There are some mismatches between the personality and behaviour of the characters, which makes the series fairly inconsistent and incomprehensible to watch at times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The climax of the series in Season 2 (NEXT), while logically sound, is highly improbable. A quick non-spoiler context-setting: for certain reasons, the male protagonist starts avoiding everyone else. The entire crew then proceeds to &lt;em&gt;never approach the guy&lt;/em&gt; to seek clarification or fix their relationship; instead, this story-based conflict ends from an absurd event that can be described as “important information in audio, useless visuals at the back”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The series establishes its own manner of troupes; a classic routine in each scene would be: Kashiwazaki Sena does something, Mikazuki Yozora rebukes this, Hasegawa Kodaka sighs. Another classic routine would be as follows: Shiguma Rika does something, Hasegawa Kodaka pretends to be oblivious, Shiguma Rika rebukes with disappointment. Established routines are dangerous for an anime in the genre of “Slice-of-Life”; being predictable is one way to lose audience attention and general interest to the series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite its flaws, I was able to follow along the story to the very bitter end; there were some enjoyable and memorable parts that were &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; relevant to the “romance” part of the series, such as the pool incident with Sena and the various flashback scenes by Kodaka. For a romance anime, however, the almost non-existent slope in relationship building thanks to Kodaka’s faults leaves much to be desired. By the end of NEXT, he makes up his mind to do something about it, but there has not been a Season 3 since 2013.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would not recommend watching “I don’t have many friends” unless you run out of anime in your bucket list (i.e. improbable). Instead, you should watch Oregairu, Bunny Girl Senpai and Shigatsu wa Kimi no Uso; if you haven’t already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Coding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CodingIndex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James</name></author><summary type="html">After enjoying Oregairu, I still had some time before all the Winter 2021 anime finished airing, so I decided to pick up “Boku wa Tomodachi ga Sukanai” as an apt alternative; this review covers both Season 1 and Season 2 (NEXT).</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/3/44724.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/3/44724.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Yahari Ore no Seishun Love Comedy wa Machigatteiru</title><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Yahari-Ore-no-Seishun-Love-Comedy-wa-Machigatteiru/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Yahari Ore no Seishun Love Comedy wa Machigatteiru" /><published>2021-04-18T00:46:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-04-18T00:46:00+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Yahari-Ore-no-Seishun-Love-Comedy-wa-Machigatteiru</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Yahari-Ore-no-Seishun-Love-Comedy-wa-Machigatteiru/">&lt;p&gt;This review covers both Season 1, 2 (Zoku) and 3 (Kan). I binged this series while waiting for the Winter 2021 anime to finish airing; and I’ve got to say, I didn’t expect to enjoy it so much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps watching this anime filled the gaps I had during my school life; for the most part, my schooling years was spent perfecting my craft, earning accolades from my dream industry and securing my future amidst the highly volatile environment we live today. Truth to be told, while I am comfortably progressing with my life thanks to the effort-laden past, I can’t help but regret having a ghostly social presence in my classes as I pursued my goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a recluse, I turned to high school anime to see what could have been - luckily, it seemed that the “social-outcast-turned-romantic-high-school-life” troupe is pre valiant in the high-school romance anime genre. In less abstract terms, I resonated well with certain characteristics of the characters in the anime; easily misunderstood, always conforming and socially distant due to pure disinterest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;story&quot;&gt;Story&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/strong&gt;: I am an anime-only consumer of this series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cliché. Or is it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps ‘standard’ is the closer descriptor - in the other high school romance anime, there is always a differentiating factor that stands out; in “&lt;a href=&quot;/anime/Kaguya-Sama-Love-Is-War/&quot;&gt;Kaguya-sama&lt;/a&gt;”, that would be the “intelligence war” waged between the love interests, in “Bunny-Girl Senpai”, that would be the supernatural ‘curses’ that befall each character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Oregairu (short-form of the series), I personally believe that the &lt;em&gt;characters&lt;/em&gt; themselves are the differentiating factor. The complexities between each character’s personalities causes conflicts that spark plot progression - an astute example would be the conduct of the prom, which is the premise of the entire third season, and also what I believe is the last conflict before the climax of the entire series. The relationships between the main characters are progressive and consistent with their behaviour at that point of time - for instance, in a bid to preserve the group’s status quo (as friends and not romantic partners), all three of them purposefully grew distant from one another, only to come back together for a surprise aquarium visit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20210418_1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 400px; width: 100%; margin: 0 auto; display: block;&quot; alt=&quot;Hikigaya on the ugliness of something genuine&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center text-gray lh-condensed-ultra f6&quot;&gt;Hikigaya during the final conversation at the Sunset | Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://beneaththetangles.com/2017/05/15/hachiman-hikigaya-and-the-ugliness-of-something-genuine/&quot;&gt;BeneathTheTangles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later on, Hikigaya finally steps out of his comfort zone, and wishes for something genuine. The group intrinsically understands that despite the status quo being on its last legs, they have to move on, which creates the force required for plot progression in Season 3 (Kan).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The self-awareness presented by all the characters in the anime about their own characteristics and how it interacts with others are subtle yet effective; which makes every emotion and thought genuine and capturing the attention of the viewer to provide the “romance” and “drama” elements demanded from Oregairu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In essence, what you should be looking out for in Oregairu is how the characters interact with one another; the other plot elements, such as the events that they are working on, and the situation that is being dealt with are less important in the grand scheme of things. If you still need further convincing, just take a look at this short clip of the two Hikigaya siblings interacting with one another:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe style=&quot;margin: 0 auto; display: block;&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/6a_HB-6tI_I&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;mt-2 text-center text-gray lh-condensed-ultra f6&quot;&gt;That scored pretty high in my book | Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6a_HB-6tI_I&quot;&gt;Kashimuiko Chan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For context, Hikigaya Hachiman used to only trust and care for his sister; she is a key support pillar for most of the conflicts in Oregairu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;characters&quot;&gt;Characters&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oregairu is an anime that uses its side-characters well. These characters are usually the source of a conflict or a progression device; some prominent examples include Yukinoshita Haruno (Yukino’s sister), who causes Yukino a great deal of stress for being compared to, and Isshiki Iroha, who generates endless problems for Hikigaya’s crew to work on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, for characters such as Hikigaya Komachi, they serve as supporting pillars for the main characters, dutifully and obviously filling gaps between major events in the anime for continuity. In fact, it can be seen quite regularly, where Komachi goes through an entire comedic routine with her brother about being oblivious to her intentions of leaving Hachiman and Yukino alone, together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of Oregairu characters, with the exception of Totsuka Saika and Zaimokuza Yoshiteru have relevant backstories and “powerful positions” for plot continuity; a good example being Hiratsuka Shizuka having the status of a teacher, which allows the main characters to form a club, interact with the Parent-Teacher committee and influence the school to make a decision otherwise impossible for the plot device (student council) or main characters alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dynamics of the characters are also well protrayed - the realism presented by Hikigaya pairs well with the flawless and logical Yukinoshita, and contrasts properly with his sister, Komachi. Furthermore, Hikigaya has good mentor-student dynamics with Shizuka-sensei, with the latter even stating that Hikigaya is much like herself, which makes the relationship feel closer to a life senior rather than a traditional teacher and student relationship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the story progresses, the behaviours change - the writing is done well enough such that the changes are continuous and expected rather than sudden; this portrays growth to the viewers, which keeps the series engaging for the viewers through a “fresh-every-second” manner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;audiovisuals&quot;&gt;Audiovisuals&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oregairu, as of writing, has aired on 2013 (season 1), 2015 (season 2), and 2020 (season 3), throughout which the audiovisuals improved steadily. The pinnacle of artstyle and music in the series is expectedly achieved in 2020, although the quality of audiovisuals were more than sufficient to convey the right mood for all three parts of the series no matter the scene.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is nothing else that stands out for the audiovisuals; which might be a good thing considering the main focus of the anime should be within its dramatic elements. Nevertheless, seeing as how &lt;a href=&quot;/anime/Shigatsu-wa-Kimi-no-Uso/&quot;&gt;Shigatsu wa Kimi no Uso&lt;/a&gt; was able to elevate the experience with the soundtrack, I can’t help but feel that much is desired as I watched Oregairu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frankly, I only enjoyed Oregairu a lot because of my circumstances - perhaps if you led a more socially fulfilling life, you would have found Oregairu boring. Nevertheless, I believe that as long as you are okay with gradual plot development and seemingly long arcs, then I think you’ll find Oregairu quite an enjoyable watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Coding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CodingIndex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James</name></author><summary type="html">This review covers both Season 1, 2 (Zoku) and 3 (Kan). I binged this series while waiting for the Winter 2021 anime to finish airing; and I’ve got to say, I didn’t expect to enjoy it so much.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/11/49459.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/11/49459.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Your Lie in April</title><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Shigatsu-wa-Kimi-no-Uso/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Your Lie in April" /><published>2021-02-15T01:50:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-02-15T01:50:00+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Shigatsu-wa-Kimi-no-Uso</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Shigatsu-wa-Kimi-no-Uso/">&lt;p&gt;“What, you haven’t watched Your Lie in April? You call youself a weeb???” is the reaction I get when I shyly proclaim that among the 200+ anime I have watched, the highly rated Shigatsu no Uso wasn’t one of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For good reason, really. I guess, I forget :stuck_out_tongue_winking_eye:? &lt;em&gt;Anyway&lt;/em&gt;, putting all that aside, I went into Your Lie in April with high expectations, with my main judging criteria being how they set up the atmosphere for emotional scenes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;atmosphere&quot;&gt;Atmosphere&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah, that’s right. I’m reviewing an anime first and foremost by it’s atmosphere, rather than its story, audiovisuals or character building. I want to explain that it’s due to the anime being of the “Drama” genre, but honestly, it’s mostly because I was bombarded with opinions stating how “emotional” the anime is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my (not-so) humble opinion, atmosphere contributes greatly to the “feels” of a scene; atmosphere is comprised of audiovisuals, pretext, and silences. Your Lie in April is an excellent example of setting up atmosphere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Characters themselves give poetic pretexts, using similes, metaphors and symbolism to express their feelings. Sometimes their feelings are compared to the sea of stars, sometimes to the flow of time, and sometimes to the vibrancy of colors. During the climax of the emotional moment, the audiovisuals turns the poems into visible/audible images, which is enhanced greatly by the classical music playing in the background, until - silence. In a sense, the atmosphere matches perfectly with most classical music pieces, as the ample silence in most pieces becomes more deafening than the music itself, building time for the audience to breathe, and to take it all in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20210215_3.gif&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 400px; width: 100%; margin: 0 auto; display: block;&quot; alt=&quot;Shigatsu no Uso Atmosphere&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center text-gray lh-condensed-ultra f6&quot;&gt;An example of atmosphere | Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pinterest.com/pin/278026976972590889/&quot;&gt;Pinterest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a little hard to put into words, but imagine composing a poem while looking at the stars, with someone playing slow tempo piano music at the side - it is bound to trigger some emotions. In a nutshell, Your Lie in April is an excellent example of setting up atmosphere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;character-building&quot;&gt;Character Building&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is good stuff. You will see a lot of character building in Your Lie in April. Take my word for it, explaining it will ruin the story for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;story&quot;&gt;Story&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your Lie in April is &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; predictable; but the predictability is also its charm. It is &lt;em&gt;because&lt;/em&gt; you can predict the events, that the scenes become more so emotional; to put simply, surprise is an element that overrides most emotions, and it should be used sparingly in a Drama-genre anime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get why people scorn me for having the audacity of calling myself a weeb when I haven’t seen Your Lie in April. This was a great watch, and something that I’ll remember as a fundamental and reference for future drama anime. Place it at the top of your “to-watch” list if you haven’t already watched it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Coding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CodingIndex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James</name></author><summary type="html">“What, you haven’t watched Your Lie in April? You call youself a weeb???” is the reaction I get when I shyly proclaim that among the 200+ anime I have watched, the highly rated Shigatsu no Uso wasn’t one of them.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/3/67177.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/3/67177.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Dungeon ni Deai wo Motomeru no wa Machigatteiru Darou ka III</title><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Dungeon-ni-Deai-wo-Motomeru-no-wa-Machigatteiru-Darou-ka-III/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dungeon ni Deai wo Motomeru no wa Machigatteiru Darou ka III" /><published>2021-02-15T01:40:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-02-15T01:40:00+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Dungeon-ni-Deai-wo-Motomeru-no-wa-Machigatteiru-Darou-ka-III</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Dungeon-ni-Deai-wo-Motomeru-no-wa-Machigatteiru-Darou-ka-III/">&lt;p&gt;From my &lt;a href=&quot;/anime/Dungeon-ni-Deai-wo-Motomeru-no-wa-Machigatteiru-Darou-ka-II/&quot;&gt;previous review&lt;/a&gt;, I mentioned that Season II was meant to be an information-revealing season, so that big “stuff” can happen in Season III.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And guess what, I’m mostly on the mark! Season III presents us with the series’ greatest conflict yet; so controversial that even members of the Hestia familia had differing opinions on the matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So controversial, that even the gods themselves bicker bitterly with one another to no resolution - this is the season that changes the plot of the series forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;story&quot;&gt;Story&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m very happy with the story; although predictable, the authors took the right step forward by introducing a difficult situation for the main characters to handle. This creates opportunities for character development and world development, alongside keeping us, the audience, on our toes as we anticipate what may happen next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, story elements are placed early enough in the season to count certain major events as “consistent” with the lore; for an example of a “major event” it would be something like reviving a person. In other words, for me to exclaim: “yup, that seems legit” to something like reviving a person, the story has to have some plot device early enough in the season to serve as a logical fact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;character-development&quot;&gt;Character Development&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not much of that here, except for the new main character introduced in this season. Arguably, in this context, this might be a good thing; because character consistency to resolve issues the way the viewer’s expect is what we need to see during a turbulent world event. In some anime, where both the character and world grows together, a character’s actions become difficult to understand as the audience simultaneously tries to grasp what is going on with the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Season III was an interesting season, and laid some story elements that can be used in the climax of the later seasons. I hope to see great things from Dungeon ni Deai wo Motomeru no wa Machigatteiru Darou Ka IV!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Coding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CodingIndex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James</name></author><summary type="html">From my previous review, I mentioned that Season II was meant to be an information-revealing season, so that big “stuff” can happen in Season III.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1523/108380.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1523/108380.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>