<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/feed/anime.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-10-05T12:03:50+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/feed/anime.xml</id><title type="html">CodingIndex’s Random Shenanigans | Anime</title><subtitle>A (human) index that likes to code. Also drinks way too much coffee.</subtitle><author><name>James</name></author><entry><title type="html">A Certain Scientific Railgun T</title><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Toaru-Kagaku-no-Railgun-T/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Certain Scientific Railgun T" /><published>2020-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Toaru-Kagaku-no-Railgun-T</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Toaru-Kagaku-no-Railgun-T/">&lt;p&gt;It’s here, it’s here, it’s here! Fresh from the oven (if fresh constitutes of a 10-day delay), we have the third season starring our beloved third-ranked Level 5 esper!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the failure that is “&lt;a href=&quot;/anime/A-Certain-Magical-Index-iii/&quot;&gt;A Certain Magical Index III&lt;/a&gt;”, many fans were disappointed by the incomprehensible finale due to it’s intense pacing and bad story-telling. Luckily for the anime, the saving grace that is “&lt;a href=&quot;/anime/Toaru-Kagaku-no-Accelerator/&quot;&gt;A Certain Scientific Accelerator&lt;/a&gt;” aired shortly after, making up for the bad taste left by “A Certain Magical Index III”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first saw “A Certain Scientific Railgun T”’s PV video, I basically leaped out of my seat in excitement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; style=&quot;margin: 10px auto; display: block;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/UtbOfkPz-G0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center text-gray lh-condensed-ultra f6&quot;&gt;PV2 | Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UtbOfkPz-G0&quot;&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;railgun&quot;&gt;Railgun&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me introduce you to everyone’s favourite tsundere biri-biri girl, Misaka Mikoto:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20201005_1.gif&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 400px; width: 100%; margin: 0 auto; display: block;&quot; alt=&quot;rAiLgUn&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center text-gray lh-condensed-ultra f6&quot;&gt;Shoooting beams with a coin | Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://tenor.com/view/toaru-kagaku-no-railgun-t-misaka-mikoto-anime-fight-railgun-gif-16037317&quot;&gt;Tenor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the “A Certain Magical Index” series, she’s seen as comedic relief, and sometimes supports the main character, although she usually fails to address the main problem because it’s magic on one end, and “&lt;em&gt;science&lt;/em&gt;” on the other. Unlike Kamijou Touma, and alike Accelerator, Misaka Mikoto lives on the side of science as one of the city’s top espers (yeah, “&lt;em&gt;science&lt;/em&gt;”).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her affection for the city, her friends and &lt;em&gt;some side effects&lt;/em&gt; causes her to blip in and out of the “dark side of the city”, which we see in greater detail in the anime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;vs-accelerator&quot;&gt;vs Accelerator&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both “A Certain Scientific Accelerator” and “A Certain Scientific Railgun” have overlapping settings, but as you can tell from both of my reviews (and the community’s rating on MyAnimeList), the clear favourite is “A Certain Scientific Railgun”. Why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me, the main reason is the &lt;strong&gt;shown&lt;/strong&gt; psychological level of conflict faced by both characters. On one hand, Accelerator is the top esper in the entire city, having enough power to absolutely crush the second-ranked esper &lt;em&gt;while&lt;/em&gt; being physically crippled. Even though he is no longer the able-bodied Accelerator, he &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; discovers a way to increase his powers, destroy his opponents and live happily ever after.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Accelerator, being on top of law enforcement itself due to his sheer ability, faces no psychological conflicts after &lt;em&gt;a certain series of events involving a side effect of Misaka Mikoto&lt;/em&gt;, no social backlash, no troubles of common man, and no obligations to fulfill; other than to protect a certain someone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20201005_2.gif&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 400px; width: 100%; margin: 0 auto; display: block;&quot; alt=&quot;A Certain Someone&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center text-gray lh-condensed-ultra f6&quot;&gt;A Certain Someone | Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tumblr.com&quot;&gt;Tumblr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, Railgun is considered “balanced” by being third-ranked. Being sandwhiched between Level 5 espers causes her to be closer to common man compared to Accelerator, which we do see reminders of in the anime: (i) just like the other students, she’s gravely afraid of the dorm fellow, (ii) she has an interest in Gekota, a mascot character of some sort, commonly seen as childish and (iii) she mostly follows the rules, even though she could probably be above them like the other Level 5s if she wanted to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These limiters, combined with her simple philosophy of “if you hurt my friends or my city, I’ll make you pay”, makes her story intriguing; in one of the episodes, she is &lt;em&gt;limited&lt;/em&gt; by sticking to the rules, which resulted in her friends getting hurt one way or another. As a viewer, you’ll feel frustrated as you watch the anime, and think something along the lines of: “If Misaka was there, this incident would be over in a heartbeat, and no one would have been hurt”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;other-reasons-why-a-certain-scientific-railgun-t-is-good&quot;&gt;Other reasons why A Certain Scientific Railgun T is good&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve got to say, “A Certain Scientific Railgun”’s supporting cast is top-tier. There are two reasons why I think so: (i) Railgun has a top-tier clique and (ii) the rare interaction between &lt;em&gt;individuals&lt;/em&gt; from the dark side and the light side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine a team comprising of a teleporter, a railgun, a hacker and a 6th sensor, all trained to trust and support each other. It’s quite unimaginable, innit? The teleporter-railgun duo has gotten so popular that it became a saying within the “A Certain Magical Index” series:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; style=&quot;margin: 10px auto; display: block;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/s3GZgWrKbJw&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center text-gray lh-condensed-ultra f6&quot;&gt;Misaka railguns a car | Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=s3GZgWrKbJw&quot;&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you think a teleporting railgun is nothing impressive, or you can’t imagine why it’d be impressive, here’s a clip for you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; style=&quot;margin: 10px auto; display: block;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/echT7Ymj3-g&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center text-gray lh-condensed-ultra f6&quot;&gt;Teleporting railgun | Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=echT7Ymj3-g&quot;&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Railgun T also shows the rare interaction between two characters from different sides of the city - one from the light side, and the other from the dark side. This is interesting because if you have watched the other anime within the main series, these characters appear outright villainous with sadistic personalities and seem to hate life itself. It’s quite refreshing knowing that these villains are still human at heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One more thing other than the top-tier supporting cast is the interesting and creative story-telling devices. I won’t go too much into it because of the spoilers, but whenever I see these devices, I think: “Is this another episode of Doraemon?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A Certain Scientific Railgun T” is a wonderful anime. It has good visuals, sound, an epic opening (the first one’s from fripSide, it literally cannot be bad), and  an engaging story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve already watched the other Toaru-series anime, watch this one too. You definitely don’t want to miss it, and it doesn’t even cost you a lot of time (25 episodes * 20 minutes per episode == 8 hours 20 minutes, just sacrifice your sleeping schedule and breakfast and you’re good).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve never watched the Toaru anime, I recommend you to start from “A Certain Magical Index” (I to III), and then “A Certain Scientific Accelerator”, then all three “A Certain Scientific Railgun” anime. It’ll only take you about a week, just ignore your responsibilities!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Note: Some remarks are satire. Satirical identification is left for the reader as an exercise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Coding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CodingIndex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James</name></author><summary type="html">It’s here, it’s here, it’s here! Fresh from the oven (if fresh constitutes of a 10-day delay), we have the third season starring our beloved third-ranked Level 5 esper!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1819/103287.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1819/103287.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Fate/stay night Movie: Heaven’s Feel - III. Spring Song</title><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Fate-stay-night-Movie-Heavens-Feel-III-Spring-Song/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fate/stay night Movie: Heaven’s Feel - III. Spring Song" /><published>2020-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Fate-stay-night-Movie-Heavens-Feel-III-Spring-Song</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Fate-stay-night-Movie-Heavens-Feel-III-Spring-Song/">&lt;p&gt;Finally, finally, finally! The final installment of the Heaven’s Feel route, arguably the best route of Fate/stay night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a long-time Fate fan (minus the Visual Novel, bite me), I inevitably spoiled parts of the Heaven’s Feel trilogy for myself, long before Ufotable announced an adaptation. That being said, the last time I watched a Fate/stay night series was &lt;a href=&quot;/anime/Fate-stay-night-Movie-Heavens-Feel-II-Lost-Butterfly/&quot;&gt;back in 2019&lt;/a&gt;, and I’ve forgotten most of the story that transpired in the first and second installment of the trilogy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence, here are my two cents for those who want to watch Heaven’s Feel - III. Spring Song: re-watch the first and second movie in the trilogy. This trilogy is so much better binged, as one would be more emotionally connected to the characters and better understand the struggles they face in Heaven’s Feel - III. Spring Song.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From this point on, let me proclaim that this review would have some spoilers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;ufotable&quot;&gt;Ufotable&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While you’re not looking, Ufotable can probably deploy a pro-money EX rank Reality Marble to create unlimited budget productions complete with god-level art, convincing sound effects and attention-grabbing voice acting. For those uninitiated, Ufotable is the studio that animated &lt;a href=&quot;/anime/Kimetsu-no-Yaiba/&quot;&gt;Kimetsu no Yaiba&lt;/a&gt; and some notable Fate franchise series like Fate/stay night: Unlimited Blade Works and Fate/Zero.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is therefore not a stretch to say that this movie was &lt;em&gt;artful&lt;/em&gt;. This time, there was not much in the way of flashy lights and epic battles like in II. Lost Butterfly; instead, the atmosphere and vital story elements were greatly emphasized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;(Spoilers) For example, when Tohsaka Rin was tossing the Zeltrech Jeweled Sword heirloom to Matou Sakura during their battle, the scene was in slow motion. It emphasized the fact that Rin was throwing away one of her only advantages, especially after a speech about how one sister had to suffer while the other lived a “blessed” life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;(Spoilers) Emiya Shirou’s night scenes, Kotomine Kirei’s church and the Greater Grail’s location were all great examples of amazing atmosphere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sound effects in III. Spring Song was top-notch and on-point. You’d find yourself in a super loud scene, only for it to become deafeningly quiet to emphasize something on-screen, like somebody dodging something, or the sound of a blade cutting through flesh, or a scene where someone detects the presence of a Servant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The voice acting was great. I was already convinced about this after a certain Matou Sakura scene in II. Lost Butterfly ( ͡° ͜ʖ ͡°), but being able to convey emotions coherent with the struggles of the character is powerful when capturing attention from the viewers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;type-moon-story&quot;&gt;Type-Moon Story&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some gripes I had for the story illustrated by the movie (spoilers):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Artoria was able to easily mana burst her way out of Medusa’s Mystic Eyes of Petrification. These were Jewel-ranked Mystic Eyes that are so excessively powerful that required sealing so that she doesn’t just petrify random folk on the street, or, in the worst case scenario, her own master. While Artoria had A++ mana, she had already started the petrification process - there shouldn’t be a way to stop this effect. I almost uttered “what the heck” out loud when I saw this;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Medusa was no longer able to use Mystic Eyes of Petrification afterwards, despite having her eyes open;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The time allocated to explain the power of Nine Lives Blade Works was way too short. In other routes, the full-blown Archer was unable to take all nine lives of Hercules, but somehow, in III. Spring Song, a Shirou with an Archer arm manages to do so with a few swings. While I understand Shirou’s internal daydream with Archer as he utilizes Archer’s arms (he surpasses Archer temporarily), Hercules is a beast of a Servant and shouldn’t be so easily defeated;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why did it take so long to get the key of the Holy Grail? Where’s Sakura during all that?;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Illyasviel von Einzbern succumbed way too quickly to Emiya Shirou’s Harem Protagonist EX skill;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What motivation did Kotomine Kirei have when he helped Emiya Shirou? Was it just curiosity?;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Seems way too convenient that Zabinya only works on very particular hearts, which includes the hearts of many people EXCEPT Kotomine Kirei due to some plot-filler involving Gilgamesh being incorruptible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having these gripes does not redirect my focus on the best parts of the story though: (i) consequences are real, (ii) inner struggles are real and should never be undermined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;(Spoilers) The trilogy depicts the True End for the Heaven’s Feel route. In this ending, Illyasviel uses the Third Magic (guess the name of this magic, it’s in the title) to save Shirou’s soul, which completely dissociates him from his body. With the help of Touko Aozaki, another character in the Nasuverse, his soul is placed into a doll and the crew live happily ever after with no revives. Shirou doesn’t get revived with his real body, the Matou family is dead, and sadly, Illyasviel doesn’t come back. Consequences are mostly actually consequences, which makes the ending more satisfying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;(Spoilers) The entire trilogy is about inner struggles, especially revolving about Shirou’s aspirations to become an Ally of Justice vs saving Sakura, an enemy of Justice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the spoilers haven’t driven you away from watching the movie, you should most definitely give the entire trilogy a shot. Despite some problems with the story, I love the Fate franchise too much to pick on the technicalities based on my vastly useless knowledge from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://typemoon.fandom.com/wiki/Heaven%27s_Feel_(route)&quot;&gt;TypeMoon Wikia&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Ufotable has an unbeatable EX rank pro-money Reality Marble for a Noble Phantasm, you should still watch Fate/stay night Movie Heaven’s Feel III. Spring Song from your local cinema :video_camera:; good anime should always be appreciated as an investment for even better anime in the future!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Coding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CodingIndex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James</name></author><summary type="html">Finally, finally, finally! The final installment of the Heaven’s Feel route, arguably the best route of Fate/stay night.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1400/104685.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1400/104685.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Toilet-bound Hanako-kun</title><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Jibaku-Shounen-Hanako-kun/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Toilet-bound Hanako-kun" /><published>2020-08-20T17:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-08-20T17:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Jibaku-Shounen-Hanako-kun</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Jibaku-Shounen-Hanako-kun/">&lt;p&gt;My first impressions of “Toilet-bound Hanako-kun” was “ah, this is going to be another one of those romance anime where drama will ensue on who gets the girl and whatnot”. Then I looked at the genres.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Eh? Where’s the drama tag? Or the romance tag?”, I say as I tried cross-referencing the cover with the genre tags, as if trying to find a connection between two seemingly unrelated suspects in a convoluted murder case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20200821_1.gif&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 400px; width: 100%; margin: 0 auto; display: block;&quot; alt=&quot;Crazy Wall&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center text-gray lh-condensed-ultra f6&quot;&gt;Trying to connect the dots | Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://giphy.com/explore/conspiracy-theory&quot;&gt;Giphy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-i-loved-about-toilet-bound-hanako-kun&quot;&gt;What I loved about Toilet-bound Hanako-kun&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I loved the unique style the anime uses to perform story-telling. Instead of animating the whole thing, they make use of still frames to present information, which works very well with the light-hearted side of the anime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also liked how the anime keeps the viewers on their toes whenever secondary information (i.e. information through gossip) is presented - there is always more than meets the eye. Keeping the viewer constantly guessing is a sure-fire way to retain engagement, alongside the constant flipping between light-hearted daily occurrences, mystery and action elements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visually speaking, the art style is cutesy and easy to look at, serving as a contrasting point to the darker elements within the anime. It’s kind of like “gap-moe” but for story-telling. It is very easy to discern when a moment is supposed to be cute, or emotional and heavy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Extra points:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the voice-acting; they’re pretty much on-point.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the storyline was enjoyable to watch and easy to digest.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;relationship between characters were well-defined and is logical due to circumstances.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-i-think-could-be-improved&quot;&gt;What I think could be improved&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Toilet-bound Hanako-kun was great, with every episode having a problem that requires resolution. However, the progress towards reaching the underlying plot’s “main goal” or “main conflict” is moving at a tortoise’s pace - in fact, I believe that the first “real” conflict hasn’t even been resolved yet, despite the long 12 episodes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is fine to perfect the environment around which the main story takes place, but taking too long might cause the viewers to forget they aren’t actually watching a slice-of-life anime. I had to keep telling myself that: “no, this is not a slice-of-life anime, there’s a deeper lore here” whenever I encounter a plot device for the main plot as I watched the anime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusions&quot;&gt;Conclusions&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, I can’t wait to see what Season 2 of “Toilet-bound Hanako-kun” brings to the table. There is room for even more character development for our main cast, which I believe can only progress should the climax of the main plot present itself in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Give “Toilet-bound Hanako-kun” a watch!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Coding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CodingIndex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James</name></author><summary type="html">My first impressions of “Toilet-bound Hanako-kun” was “ah, this is going to be another one of those romance anime where drama will ensue on who gets the girl and whatnot”. Then I looked at the genres.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1700/104788.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1700/104788.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Gakkougurashi!</title><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Gakko-Gurashi/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Gakkougurashi!" /><published>2020-08-20T16:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-08-20T16:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Gakko-Gurashi</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Gakko-Gurashi/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; Late &amp;amp; short review. You know what, I like Gakkougurashi. Not because the girls are cute, or the background is particularly interesting, but because of the character dynamics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each and every one of these characters are fighting for survival both physically, and mentally. They all dependent on each other as a team, and losing even one of them would have detrimental effects on team morale and survival. The plot involves keeping a person insane (yes, as in mentally unwell) to brighten up their lives during long periods of isolation. That’s genius.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the characters have clearly defined roles with predictable personalities and sad backstories, but yet contribute in their own meaningful way towards achieving the common goal of “survive”, and “find survivors”. It’s nothing as grandiose as “save the world”, but it is nevertheless an engaging experience as we explore the world and characters of Gakkogurashi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one of the few anime that forced me to read the manga to find out the rest of the story - the character development, world building and plot progression &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; the anime is absolutely bonkers. In the manga, the ending is wonderfully executed, putting a closure to an anime that I never thought I would like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence, for a full experience, watch the anime, then read the manga. It’ll only take you a day if you binge it all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Coding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CodingIndex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James</name></author><summary type="html">NOTE: Late &amp;amp; short review. You know what, I like Gakkougurashi. Not because the girls are cute, or the background is particularly interesting, but because of the character dynamics.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1798/91548.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1798/91548.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Ascendance of a Bookworm</title><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Honzuki-no-Gekokujou-Shisho-ni-Naru-Tame-ni-wa-Shudan-wo-Erandeiraremasen/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ascendance of a Bookworm" /><published>2020-08-20T16:10:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-08-20T16:10:00+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Honzuki-no-Gekokujou-Shisho-ni-Naru-Tame-ni-wa-Shudan-wo-Erandeiraremasen</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Honzuki-no-Gekokujou-Shisho-ni-Naru-Tame-ni-wa-Shudan-wo-Erandeiraremasen/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warning:&lt;/strong&gt; late &amp;amp; short review. &lt;em&gt;Another&lt;/em&gt; isekai anime! This time, there’s no OP hero, but a girl obsessed with books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet another combination that seems to work well; the execution salvaged the anime from my original perception that “this is just another isekai anime, I don’t really want to watch it”. Do note that I lied in my previous paragraph, about the “OP” part. You’ll see what I mean if you watch the anime till the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the remainder of the anime, we see that the main character try to hide her identity as she “invents” new products that she brought over from her old world, set a goal for her entrepreneurship ideals, but give it up for a more realistic plan that factored in her very (second) life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a nutshell, this was a refreshing watch; a young girl with the tendencies of a entrepreneur in another world is a concept you simply don’t experience often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy coding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CodingIndex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James</name></author><summary type="html">Warning: late &amp;amp; short review. Another isekai anime! This time, there’s no OP hero, but a girl obsessed with books.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1582/101697.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1582/101697.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Fate/Grand Order: Zettai Majuu Sensen Babylonia</title><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Fate-Grand-Order-Zettai-Majuu-Sensen-Babylonia/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fate/Grand Order: Zettai Majuu Sensen Babylonia" /><published>2020-08-20T15:55:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-08-20T15:55:00+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Fate-Grand-Order-Zettai-Majuu-Sensen-Babylonia</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Fate-Grand-Order-Zettai-Majuu-Sensen-Babylonia/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warning:&lt;/strong&gt; late &amp;amp; short review. Our gacha money did something! Rejoice fellow FGO players, for our salt amounted to an adaptation of yet another Fate anime!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those uninitiated, Fate is hands down my favourite series. Hence, I didn’t really care that I knew the entire plot from playing the game, and still watched the anime like a true devout follower of the Fate franchise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I loved every part of it; although, the technicalities of the last battle with Tiamat was, in my book, impossible. Hence, I docked a point, but otherwise this anime would have gotten a 10/10 rating from me. Not biased, of course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t wait for the other adaptations for Camelot and Solomon, they’re going to be &lt;em&gt;epic&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Play FGO. Watch the anime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Coding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CodingIndex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James</name></author><summary type="html">Warning: late &amp;amp; short review. Our gacha money did something! Rejoice fellow FGO players, for our salt amounted to an adaptation of yet another Fate anime!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1194/103420.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1194/103420.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Boku no Hero Academia 4th Season</title><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Boku-no-Hero-Academia-4th-Season/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Boku no Hero Academia 4th Season" /><published>2020-08-20T15:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-08-20T15:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Boku-no-Hero-Academia-4th-Season</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Boku-no-Hero-Academia-4th-Season/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warning:&lt;/strong&gt; late &amp;amp; short review. We’re already at the fourth season! Boku no Hero Academia is a shounen anime, which I am not normally interested in, but I’ve vested too much time to ignore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And well, Boku no Hero 4th season was a pretty good season; we even got a cliffhanger at the end to build suspense for the next season. The most memorable moment in the season was probably the climax scene; one can say that the aftermath caused a reshuffling of the cast cabinet, and the dynamics of the characters has changed somewhat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s see what Season 5 has got in store for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy coding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CodingIndex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James</name></author><summary type="html">Warning: late &amp;amp; short review. We’re already at the fourth season! Boku no Hero Academia is a shounen anime, which I am not normally interested in, but I’ve vested too much time to ignore.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1315/102961.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1315/102961.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Darwin’s Game</title><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Darwins-Game/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Darwin’s Game" /><published>2020-08-20T15:10:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-08-20T15:10:00+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Darwins-Game</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Darwins-Game/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warning:&lt;/strong&gt; Late &amp;amp; short review. Darwin’s game has an interesting synopsis, a cool storyline, and every opportunity to be a great anime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, it’s way too edgy. At the start of the anime, the motives of the main character was a series of logical thoughts for a person thrown in the middle of something supernatural, but at the end of the anime, the character development accelerates beyond the speed of light and ruins the otherwise interesting plot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watch for the cool storyline, but don’t expect too much in the form of engagement and entertainment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy coding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CodingIndex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James</name></author><summary type="html">Warning: Late &amp;amp; short review. Darwin’s game has an interesting synopsis, a cool storyline, and every opportunity to be a great anime.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1016/107222.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1016/107222.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Cautious Hero: The Hero Is Overpowered but Overly Cautious</title><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Shinchou-Yuusha-Kono-Yuusha-ga-Ore-Tsueee-Kuse-ni-Shinchou-Sugiru/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cautious Hero: The Hero Is Overpowered but Overly Cautious" /><published>2020-08-20T14:55:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-08-20T14:55:00+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Shinchou-Yuusha-Kono-Yuusha-ga-Ore-Tsueee-Kuse-ni-Shinchou-Sugiru</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Shinchou-Yuusha-Kono-Yuusha-ga-Ore-Tsueee-Kuse-ni-Shinchou-Sugiru/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warning:&lt;/strong&gt; Late &amp;amp; short review. It’s &lt;em&gt;another&lt;/em&gt; isekai anime! Studios nowadays seem to ride the wave to try creating “unique” isekai anime, like the one about the &lt;a href=&quot;/anime/The-Rising-of-the-Shield-Hero/&quot;&gt;Shield Hero&lt;/a&gt;, or the one about a &lt;a href=&quot;https://myanimelist.net/anime/38573/Tsuujou_Kougeki_ga_Zentai_Kougeki_de_Ni-kai_Kougeki_no_Okaasan_wa_Suki_Desu_ka&quot;&gt;Mother&lt;/a&gt;, or the one about a &lt;a href=&quot;https://myanimelist.net/anime/37744/Isekai_Cheat_Magician&quot;&gt;cheat magician&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what’s so different about Cautious Hero?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not so much; it’s literally about a cautious hero in an isekai setting. Like any other industry, trends will cause a flux of “creative” spin-offs; for instance, take the “-as-a-Service” suffix. People adopt the suffix left and right, and things like Platform-as-a-Service (PaaS), Dog walks as a service (DWaaS), Infrastructure-as-a-Service (CaaS) and heck, even Service as a Service (SaaS) surface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Applying the same logic for the current Isekai trend, instead of a Shield Hero, or a Hero with a Mother, or a Hero that is extremely overpowered, or a &lt;a href=&quot;/anime/That-Time-I-Got-Reincarnated-as-a-Slime/&quot;&gt;OP slime Hero&lt;/a&gt;, we instead have an OP but careful hero.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this combination kind of works, especially after the main character’s backstory is explained in the anime. Something about an overpowered character using his most powerful spell on a Level 1 slime makes me remember the days where I farmed EXP just to cheese dungeons in MMORPGs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve got nothing else to watch, you can give Cautious Hero a try; it’s surprisingly bearable despite the overwhelming influx of isekai anime from the industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy coding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CodingIndex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James</name></author><summary type="html">Warning: Late &amp;amp; short review. It’s another isekai anime! Studios nowadays seem to ride the wave to try creating “unique” isekai anime, like the one about the Shield Hero, or the one about a Mother, or the one about a cheat magician.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1715/103419.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1715/103419.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Kanata no Astra</title><link href="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Kanata-no-Astra/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kanata no Astra" /><published>2020-08-20T06:40:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-08-20T06:40:00+00:00</updated><id>https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Kanata-no-Astra</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codingindex.xyz/anime/Kanata-no-Astra/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warning:&lt;/strong&gt; Late &amp;amp; short review. Kanata no Astra is a gem of a series, with stellar (haha get it) plot, character development, and enough twist and turns to engage the viewer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cast each has their own background story that defines their current personality, being diverse enough that viewers would be able to sympathize with at least one character. Being an anime set in space, the backgrounds, challenges and reactions is in constant flux, keeping the user hooked as the underlying plot progresses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This anime also completes the entire story and has a proper ending; hence, if you’re looking for a good, wholesome watch, do give Kanata no Astra a shot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Coding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CodingIndex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James</name></author><summary type="html">Warning: Late &amp;amp; short review. Kanata no Astra is a gem of a series, with stellar (haha get it) plot, character development, and enough twist and turns to engage the viewer.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1784/106428.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/1784/106428.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>